<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
- phpMyAdmin XML Dump
- version 3.3.7deb7
- http://www.phpmyadmin.net
-
- Host: db1.xoala.net
- Generation Time: Jan 25, 2013 at 12:39 PM
- Server version: 5.5.19
- PHP Version: 5.3.3-7+squeeze9
-->

<pma_xml_export version="1.0">
    <!--
    - Database: 'whsmd'
    -->
    <database name="whsmd">
        <!-- Table courses -->
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">321</column>
            <column name="full_name">Geometry Honors</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Geom H</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">A formal Euclidean geometry curriculum is taught that includes coordinate, synthetic, and solid geometry. Students will use the Geometer&amp;rsquo;s Sketchpad to investigate geometric conjectures. Only students with high motivation, exceptional ability and demonstrated mathematical achievement should enroll in this course.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;h3&gt;Welcome!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students, parents, colleagues:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website helps you keep up-to-date with the Honors Geometry
classes taught by Mr. Gabriner and Mr. Davidson at Weston High
School. You can use the items at the left to navigate to different
pages, and of course you can click on any of the links contained in
following options:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check the Info page (where you are now) for information about
the course syllabus and other details.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find out current, past, or upcoming assignments on the
Assignments page for each section.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check on course procedures and policies, including requirements
for supplies, homework, and class participation, as well as
information on grading on the Policies page.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore Honors Geometry resources that will help you expand
your knowledge of mathematics.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Send email to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:gabrinerd@mail.weston.org&quot;&gt;Mr.
Gabriner&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:davidsonl@mail.weston.org&quot;&gt;Mr.
Davidson&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Here are the course &lt;a href=
&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/geomh/curriculum.pdf&quot;&gt;curriculum&lt;/a&gt; and the
&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/geomh/goals+objectives.pdf&quot;&gt;goals and
objectives&lt;/a&gt;.
</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;h3&gt;Supplies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need a bound lab notebook and a thin binder for your class notes, homework, returned
tests and quizzes, and handouts.
You will also need pencils, colored
pencils, erasers, lined paper, compass, protractor, graph paper, a
ruler, and a scientific calculator (it should have the sqrt, sin, cos, and
tan buttons). If you do not already have a calculator, you may
consider purchasing a &lt;b&gt;TI 83-84&lt;/b&gt; or &lt;b&gt;TI 83-84 Plus&lt;/b&gt; graphing
calculator. While they are not required for this course, you
will need them next year. A stapler, a hole punch, and a computer
will also be helpful at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homework will be assigned on a regular basis. To receive full
credit, you must have your completed assignment with you at the
beginning of class on the day on which it is due. You must also show
your work for all problems, even when you were not successful. If you
can&amp;rsquo;t solve a problem, record your attempts. Homework will be
evaluated based on the quality and effort of the end product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late homework will be accepted for half-credit if you hand it in
by the beginning of the next class after the one when it was
due, provided it shows sincere effort and full work on all
problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your homework carefully and promptly. Include the date, your
name, and the assignment number. Write the entire problem down, or at
least show enough of it so you and the teacher can tell what the
problem was! Don&amp;rsquo;t crowd your work. When you have a handout
&amp;mdash; or you&amp;rsquo;ve printed out your own copy of an assignment
&amp;mdash; you should treat it as a list of questions, not as a location
for writing your solutions! Write the solutions in your notebook.
Some homework assignments will be collected, and most will be looked
at in class. You won&amp;rsquo;t know in advance, so you should always do
a thorough job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;+2&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #FF0000;&quot;&gt;In all cases you must show your work!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s the process that will be of value to you: you&amp;rsquo;re
extremely unlikely to come across the exact same problem again, so
you need to be able to think and to communicate your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you&amp;rsquo;ll be unable to complete a solution. (Perhaps
from time to time you&amp;rsquo;ll even feel unable to begin solving a
problem successfully.) In such cases you still need to communicate
your thoughts and your attempts; your teacher won&amp;rsquo;t want to see
big white spaces instead of a solution. During the first semester
we?ll work on how you can be successful at showing your thinking
even when you can&amp;rsquo;t solve the problem. We&amp;rsquo;ll also work on
how you can productively collaborate with others and get help when
you need it: you&amp;rsquo;ll have to learn how to make distinctions
between cooperation and cheating, and how to work appropriately with
others without taking credit for their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tests &amp; Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tests will be announced well in advance, so you
will have time to study. You may not use your notes on tests, and
sometimes you may not be able to use your calculator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quizzes may or may not be announced in advance,
but you are usually allowed to use your notes on quizzes.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be an optional retake for each test,
counted as the sum of 1/3 of the original grade and 2/3 of the retake grade,
capped at a maximum grade of 83%
There are no retakes for quizzes, but the lowest quiz is dropped in each term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your grade for each quarter will be computed as a weighted average
of tests, quizzes, homework, classwork, and projects.
&lt;p&gt;You will be given a comprehensive final exam which will be worth 10% of your final grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to come to class prepared to actively
participate in class discussions and activities. Your classwork
and participation grade will count toward your quarter grade, so be
attentive, ask questions and work collaboratively with
classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you&amp;rsquo;re
absent, you&amp;rsquo;re still responsible for any material missed! Make
up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by calling a
classmate, or by sending email to your teacher, or by seeing your
teacher in school as soon as you return. You must make up any missed
tests or quizzes right away.&lt;/p&gt;
</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/mclaughlinj/geomh/a_secret_message.PDF&quot;&gt;Secret
Message!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/mclaughlinj/geomh/textbook.pdf&quot;&gt;How to read a textbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keymath.com/STORE/software/gsp.html&quot;&gt;Buy The Geometer&amp;rsquo;s Sketchpad&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href= &quot;http://www.cut-the-knot.org/pythagoras/index.shtml&quot;&gt;39 Proofs Of The Pythagorean Theorem !!!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href= &quot;http://www.lsbu.ac.uk/water/platonic2.html&quot;&gt;see the Platonic Solids in 3D animation!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href= &quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Kepler-PoinsotSolid.html&quot;&gt;See the Concave Regular Polyhedra...Try the 3-D Applets&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=
&quot;http://www.georgehart.com/virtual-polyhedra/kepler-poinsot-info.html&quot;&gt;Read more about the Kepler-Poinsot regular polyhedra&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt; 
</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">322</column>
            <column name="full_name">Geometry</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Geom</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This college-preparatory course in Euclidean Geometry develops a solid background in geometric skills and ideas and also places a significant emphasis on mathematical thinking. There is a special stress on processes such as finding patterns, investigating, making conjectures, developing appropriate habits of mind, explaining one&amp;#146;s results, making connections, argument, and proof. This approach is based on the premise that the best way to prepare students to solve problems that don&amp;#146;t yet exist is to help them develop the ways of thinking that are characteristic of mathematics and science. The approach stresses depth rather than breadth, often presenting long problems that extend throughout an entire class period or even more than one class period.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H2&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;This college-preparatory course in Euclidean Geometry uses the textbook Geometry for Enjoyment and Challenge. This program not only develops a solid background in geometric skills and ideas but also places a significant emphasis on mathematical thinking, inquiry, and exploration. There is a special stress on processes such as finding patterns, investigating, making conjectures, developing appropriate habits of mind, explaining one&amp;#8217;s results, making connections, argument, and proof.  This approach is based on the premise that the best way to prepare students to solve problems that don&amp;#8217;t yet exist is to help them develop the ways of thinking that are characteristic of mathematics and science.&amp;#8221; The approach stresses depth rather than breadth, often presenting long problems that extend throughout an entire class period or even more than one class period.
&lt;P&gt;
The year is divided into four major topics of unequal length:
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;invariance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;congruence and proof&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;similarity and trigonometry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;dissection, area, and volume&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;STRONG&gt;Topic 1&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Invariance&lt;/em&gt;, has a dual purpose. Its mathematical content includes the basic concepts and skills of geometry, with a particular emphasis on geometric transformations. And its procedural content aims to help all students develop appropriate mathematical habits of mind. These dual goals give students a strong foundation for their subsequent work.
 
&lt;P&gt;Geometric content in Topic 1 includes congruence-preserving transformations (translation, reflection, rotation); naming, defining, drawing, and constructing standard geometric shapes; parallels and perpendiculars; nets; symmetry; the Triangle Inequality; regions of lines, planes, and space; central and inscribed angles in circles; angles in triangles and other polygons; numerical and spatial invariants; and perpendicular bisectors, angle bisectors, and medians in triangles. Students study geometric transformations from a functional perspective and have opportunities to practice their algebra skills through equation-solving, matrices, and extensive use of coordinates.

&lt;P&gt;The ten habits of mind that are stressed in Topic 1 are as follows:
 
&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Picturing the visible, picturing the invisible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Analyzing and interpreting a figure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Using precise language to describe and analyze (including names, features, and definitions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Tinkering with problems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Mixing deduction with experimentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Looking for invariants&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Reasoning about processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Reasoning by continuity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Proving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Using different systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Topic 2&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Congruence and Proof&lt;/em&gt;, focuses on congruence but stresses proof as its major idea. Students learn to develop and present proofs after suitable investigation and experimentation. Geometric content includes congruence in general, congruent triangles, isometries, and further understanding of triangles and other polygons, including properties of quadrilaterals.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Topic 3&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Similarity and Trigonometry&lt;/em&gt;, stresses scale drawing, similar figures, and right-triangle trigonometry. Students apply their algebra and strengthen their knowledge of ratio and proportion; they learn mathematical principles behind similar triangles; areas, volumes, and perimeters of similar figures; scaling and similarity transformations; pi and other concepts involved in working with circles; and use of the sine, cosine, and tangent ratios. All of these examples combine conceptual work and the detailed skills involved in finding correct answers. There are many applications to map-making, scale drawings and blueprints, navigation, biology, and indirect measurement.
 
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;STRONG&gt;Topic 4&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;EM&gt;Dissection, Area, and Volume&lt;/em&gt;, concentrates on area, perimeter, volume, and the Pythagorean Theorem, with a special emphasis on dissection as a tool for research and understanding. Although students continue to investigate and explore, this topic also stresses algorithmic thinking and improvement of visualization skills. Connections with algebra return in the context of numerical problems.
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;h2&gt;Supplies&lt;/h2&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;You will need a well-organized 3-ring binder. Keep your class notes, homework, returned tests and quizzes, handouts, and blank (lined and graph) paper in it. Use labeled dividers to make one section for each of these categories. Individual teachers may have more specific requirements!&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;You will also need pencils, erasers, lined paper, graph paper, a compass, a ruler, a protractor, and a scientific calculator (one that is at least powerful enough to do square root, sin, cos, and tan). A stapler, a hole punch, and a computer will also be helpful at home.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h2&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;To receive full credit on homework assignments, you must have your completed assignment with you &lt;em&gt;at the beginning of class&lt;/em&gt; on the day on which it is due. &lt;strong&gt;You must also show your work for all problems&lt;/strong&gt;, even when you were not successful. If you can&amp;#8217;t solve a problem, record your attempts. Individual teachers will have their own homework grading procedures.&lt;/p&gt;					&lt;p&gt;Do your homework carefully and promptly. Include the date, your name, and the assignment number. (This sounds trivial, but it isn&amp;#8217;t. Without assignment numbers, it is difficult or impossible to find earlier assignments when it&amp;#8217;s necessary to refer to them.) Write the entire problem down, or at least show enough of it so you and the teacher can tell what the problem was!&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#8217;t crowd your work. When you have a handout or you&amp;#8217;ve printed out your own copy of an assignment, you should treat it as a list of questions, not as a location for writing your solutions! &lt;strong&gt;Write the solutions in your notebook. &lt;/strong&gt;Some homework assignments will be collected, and most will be looked at in class. You won&amp;#8217;t know in advance, so you should always do a thorough job.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 120%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #FF0000;&quot;&gt;In all cases you must show your work! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Answers are a penny a pound &amp;#8212; essentially worthless. It&amp;#8217;s only the &lt;b&gt;process&lt;/b&gt; that will be of value to you: you&amp;#8217;re extremely unlikely to come across the exact same problem again, so you need to be able to think and to communicate your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you&amp;#8217;ll be unable to complete a solution. (Perhaps from time to time you&amp;#8217;ll even feel unable to &lt;em&gt;begin&lt;/em&gt; solving a problem successfully.) In such cases you still need to communicate your thoughts and your attempts; your teacher won&amp;#8217;t want to see big white spaces instead of a solution. During the first semester we&amp;#8217;ll work on how you can be successful at showing your thinking even when you can&amp;#8217;t solve the problem. We&amp;#8217;ll also work on how you can productively collaborate with others and get help when you need it: you&amp;#8217;ll have to learn how to make distinctions between cooperation and cheating, and how to work appropriately with others without taking credit for their work.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;h2&gt;Tests &amp; Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests are announced well in advance, and are closed-book. However, you may use a 3&quot;&amp;#215;5&quot; index card with some notes on a test. Quizzes are unannounced, but you may use your notebook on quizzes. If you score below a B on a test, you are permitted one retake of that test. Retakes will be &amp;#8220;B-level&amp;#8221; assessments only. Before the retake, you must turn in corrections to the original assessment as well as completing any other review work assigned by your teacher. A successful retake will raise the original grade to a B. Note: No retakes are available for projects or quizzes.&lt;/p&gt;

										
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All graded assessments will have two levels: an A-level and a B-level. You may choose either one each time. The A-level assessment will, of course, be more challenging. Successful completion of the A-level assessment will result in an A; partial success will result in a lower grade. Successful completion of the B-level assignment will result in a B; partial success will result in a lower grade. The important fact to note: the highest grade that can be achieved on a B-level assignment is a B.  This policy will hold for tests, quizzes, projects, and some homework and classwork. Sometimes the completion of the A-level assignments will require knowledge of more material than that needed for the B-level ones. Such material will be clearly identified to students in class, in handouts, and on the website. At other times the A-level assignment may require completion of a more challenging or more abstract application of the same material.&lt;/p&gt;
					
					&lt;p&gt;Your grade for each quarter will be computed as a weighted average of tests, quizzes, homework, classwork, and projects. Tests will be worth roughly two to three times as much as a quiz.&lt;/p&gt;				
					
					&lt;h2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you&amp;#8217;re absent, you&amp;#8217;re still responsible for any material missed! You can keep up with your assignments by checking this website. Make up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by calling a classmate, or by sending email to your teacher, or by seeing your teacher in school as soon as you return. You must make up any missed tests or quizzes right away. If you absolutely must arrive at class late or leave early, do so as rarely as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;The most important rule to follow in class is this: &lt;font color=&quot;#FF0000&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;b&gt;First, do no harm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/font&gt;. Disturbing the work of your classmates will result in significant penalties! The second rule is to commit yourself to a serious attitude and do the work that&amp;#8217;s expected of you in and out of class. If you can follow the first two rules (and we expect that you can and will), the third rule is to participate in our community by helping your classmates learn.&lt;/p&gt;
				</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;H2&gt;General&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.classzone.com/books/geometry_concepts/page_build2.cfm?id=game&amp;ch=10&amp;CFID=48395642&amp;CFTOKEN=aa96cb-0007b751-8371-19cb-801f-831aaae30000&quot;&gt;Trig Frog Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;BR&gt;

&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathsnet.net/geometry/solid/index.html&quot;&gt;Exploring Nets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/sa_volume/index.html&quot;&gt;Surface Area and Volume Activity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
	&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review and practice &lt;a href=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/math-topic.cfm?TopicCode=rtritrig&quot;&gt;right-triangle trigonometry&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;View &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tcp-ip.or.jp/%7etoshio-t/Pento_e.html&quot;&gt;all 12 pentominoes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
							&lt;br&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;The &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.mathforum.org/students/high&quot;&gt;Math Forum at Swarthmore&lt;/A&gt; is always a wonderful source of information, ideas, links, and problems in any area of math education, including Geometry.&lt;br&gt;
							&lt;br&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Try these &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.larrydavidson.com/geometry/GSP/gsp_challenges1.html&quot;&gt;Geometer&amp;#8217;s Sketchpad Challenges&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
							&lt;br&gt;
						
						&lt;li&gt;The University of Minnesota&amp;#8217;s Geometry Center explores &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geom.umn.edu/%7edwiggins/mainpage.html&quot;&gt;Conjectures in Geometry&lt;/a&gt; with a particular emphasis on the use of dynamic geometry software, such as the Geometer&amp;#8217;s Sketchpad. You may also want to check out their &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.geom.umn.edu/&quot;&gt;home page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
							&lt;br&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Greg Frederickson, a computer science professor at Purdue, provides hundreds of links relating to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.purdue.edu/homes/gnf/book/webdiss.html&quot;&gt;dissections&lt;/a&gt; at all levels, ranging from simple puzzles to geometry problems that are far more advanced than anything we do in this course.&lt;br&gt;
							&lt;br&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.csus.edu/org/donne/&quot;&gt;John Donne&lt;/a&gt; pointed out, Weston isn&amp;#8217;t an island. Take a look at the interesting webpage for a geometry course at &lt;a href=&quot;http://math.rice.edu/%7elanius/Geom/&quot;&gt;Milby High School&lt;/a&gt; in Houston, Texas.&lt;br&gt;
							&lt;br&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Or one from a geometry course at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kutztown.edu/%7efithian/geometry.html&quot;&gt;Kutztown High School&lt;/a&gt; in Kutztown, Pennsylvania.
					&lt;BR&gt;
					&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download your &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.drscheme.org&quot;&gt;free copy of DrScheme&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Order &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.keymath.com/store/software/gsp.html&quot;&gt;the student edition of the Geometer&amp;#8217;s Sketchpad&lt;/a&gt; for only $39.95!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!--
&lt;li&gt; Download &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/medians.gsp&quot;&gt;the Sketchpad file for the &amp;#147;Sketchpad Medians Activity&amp;#148;&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You can review the whole concepts of congruence at &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/congruen/Lcongruent.htm&quot;&gt;regentsprep.org/Regents/math/congruen/Lcongruent.htm&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://e-zgeometry.com/class/class4/4.3/4.3.htm&quot;&gt;e-zgeometry.com/class/class4/4.3/4.3.htm&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;LI&gt;You can find practice problems dealing with triangle congruence on these webpages:&lt;BR&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/congruen/PracCong.htm&quot;&gt;regentsprep.org/Regents/math/congruen/PracCong.htm&lt;/A&gt;, problems #2, 5, 6, 7.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/congruen/PracCon2.htm&quot;&gt;regentsprep.org/Regents/math/congruen/PracCon2.htm&lt;/A&gt;, problems #1, 2, 4, 5.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.newark.osu.edu/thays/triangles1&quot;&gt;www.newark.osu.edu/thays/triangles1&lt;/A&gt;, problems #3, 4, 5, 7.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;

&lt;LI type=&quot;square&quot;&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.newark.osu.edu/thays/triangles3&quot;&gt;www.newark.osu.edu/thays/triangles3&lt;/A&gt;, problems #1, 3.&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;

&lt;/UL&gt;

&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Transformations&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://192.107.108.56/portfolios/d/desimone_g/discover2/1sketch6.htm&quot;&gt;Using Geometer's Sketchpad to Investigate Transformations&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;

       
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.utc.edu/~cpmawata/transformations/translations/lesson2.html&quot;&gt;Translations from the University of Tennessee at Chattanooga&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/math-topic.cfm?TopicCode=trans&quot;&gt;Translations from Oswego NY&lt;/A&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.mathsnet.net/transformations/translationb.html&quot;&gt;Some Translations from MathsNet&lt;/A&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.mathsnet.net/dynamic/translate.html&quot;&gt;More Translations from MathsNet&lt;/A&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.utc.edu/~cpmawata/transformations/reflections/lesson1b.html&quot;&gt;Reflections from the University of Tennessee at Chattanooga&lt;/A&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/reflect/Lreflect.htm&quot;&gt;Reflections in a Line&lt;/A&gt; (intuitive notions)&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/math/coreflec/reflect.htm&quot;&gt;Reflections in a Line&lt;/A&gt; (with coordinates)&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://standards.nctm.org/document/eexamples/chap6/6.4/index.htm&quot;&gt;General Practice of Translations&lt;--Ms.H G Block look here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;BR&gt;


</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">326</column>
            <column name="full_name">Intermediate Algebra</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Int Alg</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course is designed for students wishing to strengthen their algebraic skills prior to enrolling in Algebra II. The course will reinforce the use of algebraic notation to describe mathematical patterns; build algebraic fluency and intuition; work on mastery in solving first- and second-degree equations and inequalities; study functions, functional notation, and the use of linear functions as mathematical models; review basic properties and uses of exponents; explore the solution of linear systems; and study the analytical geometry of the line. Many of the skills required for mastery of the mathematics section of the MCAS exam will be dealt with during the course. Students will make use of graphing calculators and spreadsheets to develop their skills and understanding of the concepts described above.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;p&gt;This course will focus on several major themes,including: the concepts and notation of functions and algebraic expressions, the use of algebraic notation to describe mathematical patterns, solving first- and second-degree equations and inequalities, the use of equations as mathematical models and systems of equations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will build fluency in working with algebraic expressions, including fractions and exponents through various activities. Students may see the same question asked in several different ways, building mathematical reading comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is designed to prepare students for succesful completion of Algebra II. Many of the skills required for mastery of the MCAS exam will be dealt with during the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will make use of graphing calculators and computer software to develop their skills and understanding of the concepts described above.&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;h2&gt;Supplies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A well-organized notebook will be crucial. This will serve as your main resource for the class. Keep your warm ups, class notes, homework, returned tests and quizzes, handouts, and blank (lined and graph) paper in a three ring binder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You will also need a graphing calculator. Choose a TI-83, TI-83 Plus, TI-84 or TI-82.  You will be able to use this calculator in your math courses in future years as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graph paper, lined paper, a three hole punch, pencils, erasers and pens are also needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The textbook &lt;em&gt;Intermediate Algebra&lt;/em&gt;, K.E.Martin-Gay Â©1999 Prentice-Hall, should be left at home as there will be books in the classroom to use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To receive full credit on homework assignments, you must have your completed assignment with you &lt;em&gt;at the beginning of class&lt;/em&gt; on the day on which it is due. &lt;strong&gt;You must also show your work for all problems&lt;/strong&gt;, even when you were not successful. If you can&amp;#8217;t solve a problem, record your attempts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Late homework will be counted only if you have a good reason as to why you could not complete the assignment.  This should not happen frequently. Homework could be problems from the textbook, a handout given out in class or something downloaded from westonmath.org. Either way, you are responsible for the work-- no excuses.&lt;/p&gt;					&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 120%;&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #FF0000;&quot;&gt;In all cases you must show your work! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;It&amp;#8217;s only the &lt;b&gt;process&lt;/b&gt; that will be of value to you: you&amp;#8217;re extremely unlikely to come across the exact same problem again, so you need to be able to think and to communicate your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your grade for each quarter will be computed as a weighted average of class participation and preparation, tests, quizzes, homework, classwork, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;	
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tests &amp; Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tests are announced.  You may not use your notebook.  However, you may use a 3&quot;x 5&quot; index card for the test. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you score below a B on a test, you are permitted one retake of that test. Before the retake, you must turn in corrections to the original assessment as well as completing any other review work assigned by your teacher. A successful retake will raise the original grade to a B. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For quizzes that are announced, you may not use your binder.  Depending on the content of the quiz you may or may not be able to use a notecard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Homework quizzes will be given during the first ten minutes of class.  The quizzes will be open notebook. If you arrive late to class without a pass, you will lose time to work on your quiz. After the quizzes are collected, we may go through the questions as a class. It is your responsibility to take notes and ask questions if you are confused about topics on the homework quizzes.
&lt;p&gt;The quizzes will be given back the next class period, and you are allowed to complete revisions on the quiz for additional credit. Revisions must be on a separate piece of paper and must include the correct answer and what was incorrect about your original solution. You may receive up to 9 out of ten points on the quiz with revisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;									
&lt;h2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;
					&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you&amp;#8217;re absent, you&amp;#8217;re still responsible for any material missed! You can keep up with your assignments by checking this website. Make up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by calling a classmate, or by sending email to your teacher, or by seeing your teacher in school as soon as you return. You must make up any missed tests right away. If you absolutely must arrive at class late or leave early, do so as rarely as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work hard and you will learn alot in this class. Volunteer questions and solutions often. You will have many opportunities to do math during class and you should take advantage of that. Stay on task and do not disrupt other students' learning. Above all, make a positive contribution to the class.&lt;/p&gt;
				</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bpl.org/teens/mcas/G10Menu.htm&quot;&gt;www.bpl.org/teens/mcas/G10Menu.htm&lt;/a&gt; has lots of MCAS practice questions and the solutions to the questions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.carnegielearning.com&quot;&gt;www.carnegielearning.com&lt;/a&gt; gives information about computer software currently being used in this course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some percent practice websites:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathgoodies.com/lessons/vol4/challenge_vol4.html&quot;&gt;Website #1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.regentsprep.org/Regents/math/percent/PracPer.htm&quot;&gt;Website #2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;    &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amby.com/educate/math/4-2_pr_x.html&quot;&gt;Website #3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some extra websites to practice algebra:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theproblemsite.com/games/adders.asp?po=0&amp;spd=3&amp;sc=710
&quot;&gt;The Worm Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;
http://www.mathdork.com/games/asteroidsexp3/asteroidsexp3.html&quot;&gt;Asteroids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;
http://www.interactivestuff.org/sums4fun/decchall.html&quot;&gt;The Decimal Challenge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.funbrain.com/algebra/index.html&quot;&gt;Order of Operations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">331</column>
            <column name="full_name">Algebra II Honors</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Alg 2 H</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course builds upon previous work in Algebra I and Geometry by pursuing algebraic ideas in greater depth and breadth. Topics and subtopics include systems of equations and inequalities of the first and second degrees; polynomial, exponential, logarithmic, and other functions in both explicit and recursive forms; the theory of functions, including function representations, inverses, composition, domain and range; matrices; transformations of graphs; an introduction to sequences, emphasizing explicit and recursive definitions; counting, probability, and combinatorics; and an introduction to statistics. Computer programming is introduced as a topic in itself and is used throughout the course, as are graphing calculators. There is a balance between mathematical theory and its application to many endeavors, particularly mathematical modeling, cryptography, linear programming, and game theory. In all these contexts, students are expected to develop and demonstrate skills and concepts at an honors level.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H2&gt;&lt;A NAME=Syllabus&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;There are four major topics during the year:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Topic 1, Introduction to Abstract Algebra, sets the stage for the entire year. The class learns about sets, relations, binary operations, and functions. Functions are studied in many ways, as rules, machines, tables, mapping diagrams, and graphs. Composition of functions, inverses of functions, transformations of
graphs, and recursive vs. explicit definitions are all examined.
Students learn the properties of specific functions and function
families, both continuous and discrete, with an emphasis on exponential and logarithmic functions. Students are
introduced to the use of graphing calculators, to a powerful piece of mathematical software called MAPLE ,and to computer programming in a language called Scheme. This topic includes applications to mathematical modeling, especially for situations
involving exponential growth and decay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Topic 2, Statistics, starts with a brief review of students' prior
experience with data analysis from Middle School ( including
measures of center, such as mean, median, and mode ) and then
proceeds to extend those ideas to measures of spread, such as range, variance, and standard deviation. The idea of a distribution of data is emphasized. Students will develop models to fit both linear and non-linear relationships between two variables, with emphasis on ordinary least squares methods. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Topic 3, Introduction to Number Theory, starts with primes, composites,
the Fundamental Theorem of Arithmetic, factoring, divisors, greatest common divisor, and least common multiples. Modular arithmetic and the algebra of congruences is developed, and this leads to the principal
application of this topic, an extensive exploration of cryptology.
This application includes a function-based approach to cryptography using
classical ciphers such as substitution and Vigenere, modern
encryption with matrices and RSA, and a touch of cryptanalysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Topic 4, Introduction to Probability, includes systematic counting, combinations and permutations,
the definition of probability, the multiplication principle, binomial probability, the binomial theorem, and conditional probability. Applications may include genetics, detection of fraud, meedical testing, and manufacturing quality control. &lt;/p&gt;

</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;P&gt;This page describes the Algebra 2 Honors policies and procedures
concerning supplies, homework, tests and quizzes, grading, and class
participation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Supplies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;You will need a well-organized 3-ring binder. Keep your class
notes, homework, returned tests and quizzes, and handouts in it. If
you wish to take notes in a spiral or perfect-bound notebook, you are
welcome to do so but you still need a 3-ring binder for handouts
and for material that has been returned to you. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;You will also need pencils, erasers, colored pencils, lined paper,
graph paper, and a graphing calculator. You may use any graphing
calculator, but the TI-83 or TI-84 (in any of their varieties) is recommended
and will be used for class demonstrations. At home you will need a
ruler, protractor, and compass- but we'll provide them if you need
them in the classroom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;We can't require you to have a computer at home, but you
probably already do. It will be extremely useful throughout the year,
and will save you from needing to go to computer labs at school
during or after the school day. During the course we will give you information about several useful computer programs you can download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Homework is usually assigned for each class. We will usually discuss the assignment in class on the day that it is due. We will look for you to share your work on each problem with the class, even if you were not successful. Thus, answers alone, without supporting work, will not be very helpful. 
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Sometimes you'll be unable to complete a solution. (Perhaps
from time to time you'll even feel unable to begin solving a
problem successfully.) In such cases you still need to communicate
your thoughts and your attempts. During the first term
we'll work on how you can be successful at showing your thinking
even when you can't solve the problem. We'll also work on
how you can productively collaborate with others and get help when
you need it: you'll have to learn how to make distinctions
between cooperation and cheating, and how to work appropriately with
others without taking credit for their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The most valuable problems are those you really work on. Some
problems from this course you'll want to try again the next day-
indeed, sometimes we'll &quot;roll over&quot; especially challenging problems onto the next homework to get another try at them. Some of the most successful students spend a part of their homework
time revisiting past problems and trying to solve them (or resolve
them more efficiently or elegantly) using hints and ideas presented
in more recent classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Tests &amp; Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;All tests will be announced well in advance, so you will have time
to study. Usually you may not use your notes on tests, but you are often allowed a 3&quot; x 5&quot; notecard on at least part of the test. You will
almost always be allowed to use your calculators on at least part of the test, although there will often be calculator-free sections on a test or an entire
calculator-free quiz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Quizzes will not be announced in advance, but you may use notes
when taking a quiz. These must be your own notes , including
handouts, or printouts from the Web (that you have naturally filed in
your binder!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;To earn an A on a test or quiz, you must do an excellent job the
first time you take it. If you get below a B on a test or quiz,  you may have
the opportunity to retake it. You will have the opportunity to retake ONE test and ONE quiz per quarter. If you decide to retake a test or quiz,  you must make an appointment with
your teacher to review your original assessment,  and then complete any additional work your teacher decides is necessary to prepare you for the retake. Then you and your teacher will agree on a time for you to demonstrate that competence on a new assessment. Your teacher may decide
you can do this by solving problems that require it on the next
regularly scheduled test (this is the most common way of retaking a quiz), or your teacher may require that you take a
new version of the test or quiz (this is the usual way of retaking a test). You will only have ONE chance to retake a quiz or test. If you demonstrate competence on a
retake, your grade will be raised to a B (83%) and your old grade will
disappear. A grade of B demonstrates competence, whenever it has been
achieved. (Note, however, that Weston High School's grading
system does not permit carrying over work from one term to the next
so that you should not delay in scheduling appointments for review
and retakes. Generally the only retakes possible during the final
week of a marking period are for the most recent test or quiz)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Your grade for the quarter will be computed as a weighted average
of tests, quizzes, homework, projects, and class participation. Each
quiz will count as the equivalent of 50% of a test. Other than that,
all quizzes count the same, and all tests count the same. Projects can vary greatly in time and effort required. When a project is assigned, it will be given a weight for grading purposes based on the value of a quiz (a small project might be worth a quiz grade, while a larger one could be worth a quiz-and-a-half or even two quiz grades). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt; Tests, quizzes, and projects count for 85% of a term grade, with homework and classwork the remaining 15%. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you're
absent, you're still responsible for any material missed! Make
up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by looking on this website, calling a
classmate, sending an email to your teacher, or by seeing your
teacher in school as soon as you return. You must make up any missed
tests or quizzes right away. If you absolutely must arrive at class
late or leave early, do so as rarely as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Our basic rules for class:
&lt;FONT COLOR=&quot;#CC0000&quot;&gt;First, do no harm&lt;/font&gt;. Don't interfere with anyone else's learning. Second: Commit yourself to a serious attitude and do the work that's expected of you. Third: Become a part of the Algebra 2 Honors community and help your
classmates learn by participating fully in all class activities, discussions, and projects.&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;P&gt; For the beginning-of-year algebra review, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;https://dl.dropbox.com/u/49187641/Summary%20of%20Topics%20for%20Prospective%20Algebra%20II%20Honors%20Students-2.pdf&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; For the applet to crack the substitution cipher, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.math.psu.edu/dlittle/java/cryptography/monoalphabetic/index.html&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; For the Fathom Correlation Exercise, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Scatterplot Correlation Exercise.ftm&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; Mark your calendars: our first quarter test days are Tuesday, September 22 and Wednesday, October 28.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; There are many good interactive algebra review activities at  &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.analyzemath.com&quot;&gt; ANALYZEMATH. &lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;P&gt; Click here for &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Six Data Sets.ftm&quot;&gt;SIX DATA SETS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt; For the Towers of Hanoi applet, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://illuminations.nctm.org/ActivityDetail.aspx?ID=40&quot;&gt;TOWERS OF HANOI&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;P&gt;For the Fathom, Excel, or .PDF files for the Statistics Project, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/StatProjectDataRevised.ftm&quot;&gt;FATHOM PROJECT  DATA&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Stat Project Data Revised.xls&quot;&gt;EXCEL PROJECT DATA&lt;/A&gt;or &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Stat Project Data Revised.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF PROJECT  DATA&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;For the Fathom activity on pro sports salaries, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Baseball Data 2006.ftm&quot;&gt;BASEBALL SALARIES&lt;/A&gt; or &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Football Data 2006.ftm&quot;&gt;FOOTBALL SALARIES&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;For the first Fathom activity, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://online.redwoods.cc.ca.us/instruct/darnold/math15/aliaga/Chapter04/FathomHtml/index.html&quot;&gt;INTRODUCTION TO FATHOM&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;  
&lt;P&gt;For the SCHEME&amp;nbsp;1 worksheet, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Scheme%201%20Algebra%202%20Honors.pdf&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;  &lt;P&gt;For the Mountains Beyond Mountains Data, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/MBM.xls&quot;&gt;HERE.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the link to the first trees database, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/trees.ftm&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;For the link to the second trees database, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Trees%20Revisited.ftm&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For the Fathom link to normal distributions, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://online.redwoods.cc.ca.us/instruct/darnold/math15/Aliaga/Chapter06/FathomHTML/NormalDistribution.html&quot;&gt;HERE.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;Statistics Games&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://istics.net/stat/Correlations/&quot;&gt;Correlation Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruf.rice.edu/~lane/stat_sim/reg_by_eye/index.html&quot;&gt;Regression by Eye Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;A NAME=alglinks&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Algebra Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;Read &lt;A HREF=&quot; http://www.sosmath.com/algebra/logs/log4/log4.html&quot;&gt;a
   concise summary of exponential and logarithmic functions&lt;/a&gt;,
   including the properties of logs and many examples of applying
   logs.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
 
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.drscheme.org&quot;&gt;Download
   the latest version of Scheme&lt;/a&gt; for your home computer for
   free.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Try the &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.mirror.org/crypt&quot;&gt;literary
   cryptograms&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.contestcen.com/crypt.htm&quot;&gt;cryptogram
   challenges&lt;/a&gt;. Also, if you think you?re up to it, try
   decrypting one of &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.math.okstate.edu/~wrightd/crypt/maple/contest.html&quot;&gt;these
   Vigenere ciphertexts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;If you know the first few terms of a sequence, you may be able
   to find a recursive or explicit rule for it at &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.research.att.com/~njas/sequences/&quot;&gt;The
   Handbook of Integer Sequences&lt;/a&gt;. The terms have to be integers,
   and you?ll get more rules than you want unless you have a
   significant number of terms. Note also that this webpage
   doesn?t assume that you?re providing the &lt;EM&gt;first&lt;/em&gt;
   few terms, so it may give you rules for which the terms you
   provide are somewhere down the line.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;The Math Forum at Swarthmore is always a wonderful source of
   information, ideas, links, and problems in any area of math
   education, including &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://forum.swarthmore.edu/algebra/k12.algebra.html&quot;&gt;algebra&lt;/a&gt;,
   &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://forum.swarthmore.edu/library/browse/static/topic/number_theory.html&quot;&gt;number
   theory&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://forum.swarthmore.edu/probstat/probstat.html&quot;&gt;probability&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
     
   &lt;LI&gt;Michael Shackleford calls himself the
   &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.thewizardofodds.com&quot;&gt;Wizard of Odds&lt;/a&gt;. He
   provides all the information you could possibly want about games
   of chance and the application of probability to gambling. He also
   has links to frequencies of first names and various Java programs
   and games.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Did Shakespeare write about logarithms? See what &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://home.att.net/~tleary/disme.htm&quot;&gt;Penn
   Leary&lt;/a&gt; has to say about it.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;The &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.utm.edu/research/primes/&quot;&gt;Prime
   Page&lt;/a&gt; contains everything you?d want to know about prime
   numbers.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;The &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.austinlinks.com/Crypto/&quot;&gt;Quadralay
   Cryptography Archive&lt;/a&gt; has all the modern cryptology links you
   could ask for.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Not surprisingly, Texas Instruments gives you an opportunity
   to learn more about your &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://education.ti.com/&quot;&gt;TI
   calculators&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;A NAME=otherlinks&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Other Math Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.nsta.org/quantum/&quot;&gt;Quantum Magazine&lt;/a&gt; is
   a great source of challenging math and science material.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;The good folks at Harvard have provided you with &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.sparknotes.com/math/&quot;&gt;explanations
   and practice problems (along with solutions!)&lt;/a&gt; for practically
   every topic in high-school math.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Even though it suffers from blinking, the &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://coolmath.com&quot;&gt;Cool
   Math&lt;/a&gt; site contains useful links to a lot of interesting math
   sites.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
      
   &lt;LI&gt;The &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www-groups.dcs.st-and.ac.uk:80/~history/index.html&quot;&gt;history
   of math&lt;/a&gt; always provides a useful context that can inform and
   enliven what you?re learning.&lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;BR&gt;
   &lt;/li&gt;
   
 &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">332</column>
            <column name="full_name">Algebra II</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Alg 2</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course builds upon previously studied topics from Algebra I and Geometry. It develops skills and emphasizes applications of those skills. Major topics include quadratic functions, exponential and logarithmic functions, matrices, systems of equations, linear programming, cryptography, and number theory. Use of a graphing calculator is an essential component of this course; students will need access to a TI-83 or -84 calculator. Students will become more proficient in the application of technology to the study of mathematics. Applications of mathematics will be emphasized throughout the course.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;p&gt;Students, parents, colleagues:&lt;/p&gt;
         
         &lt;p&gt;This website helps you keep up-to-date with the
         college-prep Algebra II classes taught by Mr. Davidson,
Ms. Fierabend, Mr. Gacs,
and Ms. Gajewski at Weston High School. You can use the
         items at the left to navigate to different pages, which include the
         following options:&lt;/p&gt;
         
         &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Check the Info page (where you are now) for detailed
            information about the course syllabus, a calendar of
            upcoming events, and the teachers&amp;#8217; schedules.&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li&gt;Find out current, past, or upcoming assignments
on the teachers&amp;#8217; assignments pages.&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li&gt;Check on &lt;a href=&quot;/course_policies.php?course_num=332&quot;&gt;course procedures and
            policies&lt;/a&gt;, including requirements for supplies,
            homework, and class participation, as well as information
            on grading.&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li&gt;Explore &lt;a href=&quot;course_rsrc.php?course_num=332&quot;&gt;Algebra II
            resources&lt;/a&gt; that will help you expand your knowledge of
            mathematics.&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
            
            &lt;li&gt;Send email to the teachers.&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;/ul&gt;
         
         &lt;h2&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
         
         &lt;h2&gt;Syllabus&lt;/h2&gt;
         
         &lt;p&gt;This course builds upon previously studied topics from
         Algebra I and Geometry.
It develops skills and emphasizes
         applications of those skills.
Major topics include quadratic functions, exponential functions, logarithmic functions, systems of equations, linear programming,
         cryptography, and number theory.
Use of a graphing
         calculator is an essential component of this course;
         students will need access to a TI-83, -84, -83+, or -84+
         calculator both in class and at home.
Students will become more proficient in the
         application of technology to the study of mathematics,
including spreadsheets and programming.
         Applications of mathematics will be emphasized throughout
         the course.&lt;/p&gt;
         
			&lt;h3&gt;Topics of Study&lt;/h3&gt;
         
         The college-prep Algebra II course is divided into four
         major units of roughly equal length:
         &lt;ol&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/alg2/quadratics_info.html&quot;&gt;Quadratic Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/alg2/exponents_and_logs_info.html&quot;&gt;Exponential and
         Logarithmic Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/alg2/systems_info.html&quot;&gt;Systems of Equations and Inequalities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
         &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/alg2/crypto_info.html&quot;&gt; Cryptography with Number Theory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;h2&gt;Supplies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will need the following supplies, which you should have with you in class every day and otherwise
available when you are doing your math work:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binder and/or notebook as specified by your teacher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regular or mechanical pencils, colored pencils, and erasers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a ruler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a &lt;b&gt;TI-83&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;TI-83 Plus&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;TI-84&lt;/b&gt;, or &lt;b&gt;TI-84 Plus&lt;/b&gt; graphing calculator&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A stapler, a hole punch, and a computer will also be helpful at home.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Classwork and Homework&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Work will be assigned on a regular basis.
There is no distinction between classwork and homework.
If you get it done in class, just consider it classwork;
if you don&amp;#8217;t, then you&amp;#8217;ll need to finish it as homework.
It is your responsibility to check westonmath.org every day
to find out what work is due when.
If no work seems to be posted, check with your teacher to see whether
there is actually an assignment!
To receive full
credit, you must have your completed assignment with you at the
beginning of class on the day on which it is due.
You must also show
your work for all problems, even when you were not successful. &lt;b&gt;If you
can&amp;#8217;t solve a problem, record your attempts. &lt;/b&gt;Homework will be
evaluated based on the quality and effort of the end product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we will not discuss work on the day when it is due,
and sometimes we will refer back to previous assignments,
so it is important for you to hold onto back work from day to day.
Since you will be doing all your work in your bound lab notebook,
you will have no trouble holding onto it.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late work may be accepted for partial credit if you hand it in
by the beginning of the next class after it was due,
provided it shows sincere effort and full work on all
problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your work carefully and promptly in your bound lab notebook.
Include the date, your
name, and the assignment number.
Write the entire problem down, or at least show enough of it
so that you and the teacher can tell what the problem was!
Don&amp;#8217;t
crowd your work.
When you have a handout &amp;#8212; or you&amp;#8217;ve
printed out your own copy of an assignment &amp;#8212; you should treat it
as a list of questions, not as a location for writing your solutions.
Keep a copy of the questions in your &lt;i&gt;binder, &lt;/i&gt;or paste it into your lab notebook if you so wish.
In either case, write the solutions in your lab notebook.
Sometimes your work will be looked at in class,
sometimes your lab notebook will be collected,
and sometimes we will discuss it without checking it.
You won&amp;#8217;t
know in advance, so you should always do a thorough job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;+2&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #FF0000;&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt;In all cases you must show your work!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
It&amp;#8217;s the &lt;i&gt;process &lt;/i&gt;that will be of value to you: you&amp;#8217;re
extremely unlikely to come across the exact same problem again, so
you need to be able to think and to communicate your thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you&amp;#8217;ll be unable to complete a solution. (Perhaps
from time to time you&amp;#8217;ll even feel unable to &lt;i&gt;begin &lt;/i&gt;solving a
problem successfully.) In such cases you still need to communicate
your thoughts and your attempts; your teacher won&amp;#8217;t want to see
big blank spaces instead of a solution. During the first quarter
we&amp;#8217;ll work on how you can be successful at showing your thinking
even when you can&amp;#8217;t solve the problem. We&amp;#8217;ll also work on
how you can productively collaborate with others and get help when
you need it: you&amp;#8217;ll have to learn how to make distinctions
between cooperation and cheating, and how to work appropriately with
others without taking credit for their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Tests &amp; Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tests will be announced well in advance, so you will have time
to study.
Quizzes might not be announced in advance
but are usually open-note.
You may not use your notes on tests, but you will be allowed
to use a 3&amp;Prime;-by-5&amp;Prime; notecard that you have prepared in advance,
as long as you have written notes on &lt;i&gt;one side only &lt;/i&gt;in your own handwriting.
On any test or quiz there may be certain problems on which you
will not be allowed to use your graphing calculator.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You will have the opportunity to retake any test (&lt;i&gt;not quiz&lt;/i&gt;) in which you
received a grade lower than 83,
except possibly for ones that are returned during the last week of a term.
There will be a single opportunity for retaking
each test, and your grade will be adjusted by multiplying the original grade by 1/3 and the retake grade by 2/3, up to a maximum of B. In order to qualify for a retake, you must do &lt;b&gt;all&lt;/b&gt; of the following before taking the retake:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;Complete test corrections.&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;li&gt;Meet with your teacher to review the material.&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;li&gt;Complete additional problems assigned by your teacher.&lt;/li&gt;
   
  &lt;li&gt;Make an appointment for a date and time within two weeks after the original was returned (but not within the last week of the quarter).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you receive a grade below 83 on a &lt;i&gt;quiz, &lt;/i&gt;you will not be able to retake it, but the lowest quiz grade in each quarter will be dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your grade for each quarter will be computed as a weighted average
of tests, quizzes, homework, classwork, and projects.
Specific information will be given to you in class.
Longer quizzes will generally be weighted as 30&amp;ndash;40% of a test,
but shorter quizzes may be weighted much less.

Your final grade for the year will be a weighted average of the four quarters (22.5% each) and a comprehensive final exam (10%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All students are expected to come to class prepared to 
participate actively in class discussions and activities. Since your classwork
grade will count toward your quarter grade, you will want to be
attentive, ask questions, and work collaboratively with
classmates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you&amp;#8217;re
absent, you&amp;#8217;re still responsible for any material missed! Make
up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by calling a
classmate, by sending email to your teacher, or by seeing your
teacher in school as soon as you return. You must make up any missed
tests or quizzes right away.&lt;/p&gt;

         </column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;h2&gt;General&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keymath.com/DAA/online&quot;&gt;The textbook online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ccl.northwestern.edu/netlogo/download.shtml&quot;&gt;Download NetLogo.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You may legally download the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ticalc.org/archives/files/fileinfo/84/8442.html&quot;&gt;TI-83 emulator&lt;/a&gt; as long as you own a TI-83 (or higher) calculator.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/DataFlyer/&quot;&gt;Data Flyer&lt;/a&gt; (ready for your use).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quadratic Functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Exponential and Logarithmic Functions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/alg2/saving-for-college.html&quot;&gt;Saving for College: A Spreadsheet Activity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://qrc.depaul.edu/cyorke/ModifiedActivities/Activity_Linear_v_Expo.htm&quot;&gt;Linear vs. Exponential Growth: Another Spreadsheet Activity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://regentsprep.org/Regents/mathb/4B1/posnegzprac.htm&quot;&gt;Practice with Exponents.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.uww.edu/~mcfarlat/141/expo1.htm&quot;&gt;Exponents Self-Test&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ruf.rice.edu/~lane/stat_sim/reg_by_eye/index.html&quot;&gt;Regression by Eye&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Systems of Equations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cryptography and Number Theory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/alg2/crypto-resources.html&quot;&gt;Some Crypto Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;!-- These links give you access to the &lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/mccowand/alg2/stat/MBM.xls&quot;&gt;latest version of our Excel database&lt;/a&gt; of health and economic indicators for countries of the world prepared for the &lt;i&gt;Mountains Beyond Mountains &lt;/i&gt;interdisciplinary project. The &lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/mccowand/alg2/stat/readme.pdf&quot;&gt;Read Me file&lt;/a&gt; gives sources and units for each category.&lt;br&gt;
--&gt;
</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">333</column>
            <column name="full_name">Topics in Algebra II</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Topics</column>
            <column name="semesters">3</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course is designed for students who
have the interest and motivation to succeed in Algebra II but who need additional time to master the material of that course.
The Topics course offers students an opportunity for additional instruction on topics currently being studied in Algebra II, helps students diagnose background weaknesses, and offers help in remediating those weaknesses. The course improves both algebraic and arithmetic skills needed for success in higher math courses. This is a pass/fail course with little outside homework required. This course meets 2.5 blocks per eight-day cycle.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H1&gt;&lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt; WELCOME TO TOPICS IN ALGEBRA II&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;The Course &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;This course meets 2.5 times out of every 8 day rotation. &lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Students will be graded on a pass/fail basis. &lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Students will not be given extra homework or tests in this course. &lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Students will have time to ask questions and practice the topics they have learned in their algebra 2 class. &lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
Sometimes students will preview topics they have not covered yet in their algebra 2 class.
  &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   </column>
            <column name="policies">Students should come to class prepared with their calculator, pencil and algebra 2 work.</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;a href = &quot;http://www.quia.com/cb/69212.html&quot;&gt; Function Notation Practice&lt;/a&gt; here		
&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.algebrahelp.com&quot;&gt;AlgebraHelp.com&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.purplemath.com/modules/modules.htm&quot;&gt;Practical Algebra Lessons from PurpleMath&lt;/a&gt;

			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cne.gmu.edu/modules/dau/math/dau1_frm.html&quot;&gt;DAU Math Refresher&lt;/a&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://home.earthlink.net/%7edjbach/lessons.html&quot;&gt;Dan's Math Lessons&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/courses/topics/0583514q.pdf&quot;&gt;SAT/MCAS Review Problems #0583514&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/courses/topics/0813966q.pdf&quot;&gt;Systems Problems #0813966&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emsc.nysed.gov/ciai/testing/mathre/mathatestja03.pdf&quot;&gt;Not an MCAS, not an SAT...but a New York State Regents Exam&lt;a&gt;


&lt;li&gt;&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.doe.mass.edu/mcas/student/2000/g10math.html&quot;&gt;Sample grading of MCAS 2000 open response questions&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.doe.mass.edu/mcas/student/2001/g10math.html&quot;&gt;Sample grading of 2001 MCAS open response questions&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a 
href=&quot;http://www.doe.mass.edu/mcas/2002/release/g10math.pdf&quot;&gt;Previous MCAS tests in PDF format&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/education/mathsfile/gameswheel.html&quot;&gt;BBC Math Games!!!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.mazeworks.com&quot;&gt;Maze Works!&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/schools/ks3bitesize/maths/&quot;&gt;More BBC Math Resources&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.engin.umd.umich.edu/CIS/course.des/cis479/projects/tax/Taxman.html&quot;&gt;The Taxman Game&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://connectedmath.msu.edu/CD/Grade6/FactorGame/&quot;&gt;Two player Taxman&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://www.brainbashers.com/puzzles.asp&quot;&gt;Brainbashers&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.cryptograms.org/&quot;&gt;Try Solving Cryptograms!&lt;/a&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">0</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">334</column>
            <column name="full_name">Computer Science: Concepts &amp; Applications</column>
            <column name="short_name">Comp Sci: Concepts &amp; Apps</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">CSCA</column>
            <column name="semesters">2</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">3</column>
            <column name="description">This course is intended for students who want to broaden and deepen their knowledge about computers. 
Topics will include the design and structure of databases and spreadsheets, the internal workings of computers, the history of computing, artificial intelligence, and how the Internet works.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;p&gt;This lab-based course is intended for students who want to broaden and deepen their knowledge of computers in areas other than programming. Topics include the design and structure of databases and spreadsheets, the internal workings of computers, the history of computing, artificial intelligence, and how the Internet works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Themes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Representing, storing, and retrieving data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Models for creating and accessing information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communication within networks and computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What computers can do and how they do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;!-- 
&lt;h3&gt;Student Outcomes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will&amp;#133;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of databases by designing and building a database for a given task.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of multiple representations by representing the same data in a database,
a spreadsheet, and a webpage.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of... by ...&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of... by ...&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of... by ...&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt; --&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Course Content:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;b&gt;Unit 1 (Representing Data)&lt;/b&gt;, students learn how to design and build databases and spreadsheets.
Concepts include multiple representations of data,
data types, fields, calculated fields, records, layouts, tables, relations, and scripts,
as well as the similarities and differences between databases and spreadsheets.
The fundamental question is how we can represent and access data as effectively as possible.
Software applications include FileMaker, Excel, and MySQL.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;b&gt; Unit 2 (Exploring the Internet)&lt;/b&gt;, students learn how the Internet works so it no longer
feels like magic.
Concepts include the history of the Internet, the use of IP numbers
and the domain name system,
how email and webpages work, and construction of
webpages using HTML and simple Javascript. The fundamental question is how information can get from
my computer to your computer. Along the way, students explore some of the related social,
economic, and ethical issues. Software applications include a variety of browsers and text editors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;b&gt; Unit 3 (Understanding Computers)&lt;/b&gt;, students learn about the internals of computer hardware
and software. The fundamental question is how a collection of silicon and circuits
can lead all the way to sophisticated computer applications.
Ideas include binary numbers, the basics of computer architecture,
logic gates, an introduction to operating systems,
and the problem of artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Materials:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The course uses a variety of webpages in lieu of a textbook, including the following:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;How Stuff Works, &lt;/em&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howstuffworks.com&quot;&gt;http://www.howstuffworks.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;W3Schools, &lt;/em&gt;at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3schools.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.w3schools.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;h2&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please be sure that you have read the &lt;a href=&quot;info.php&quot;&gt;Course Info&lt;/a&gt; page before reading this one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 60% of our classtime will be devoted to lab work.
This means that you will usually get your assignments done during class!
But don&amp;#8217;t rush through the labs:
it&amp;#8217;s essential for you to complete your work carefully,
so that you can learn from it.&lt;/p&gt;
		
&lt;p&gt;Whether done in class, in free time, or at home, some of your assignments have components that need to be handed in.
&lt;em&gt;These must be emailed to Mr. Davidson, not handed in as printouts.&lt;/em&gt;
If you&amp;#8217;re just sending text, please put it in the body of your email message, not as an attachment.
If you&amp;#8217;re sending a computer document that isn&amp;#8217;t text, send it as an attachment.
In either case, include the assignment number clearly &lt;strong&gt;in the subject field&lt;/strong&gt;,
and &lt;strong&gt;be sure to keep your own copy&lt;/strong&gt; of the message and the attachment if there is one!
&lt;br&gt;
				&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;!-- &lt;p&gt;25% of your term grade will be based on assignments that you hand in, 25% on classwork, 25% on tests, and 25% on quizzes. All tests will be announced well in advance. Quizzes will usually &lt;i&gt;not &lt;/i&gt;be announced in advance, but are always open-note. Some tests and quizzes will be done on the computer, others will be pencil-and-paper. There will be significant penalties for late work on assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Grades below B indicate that you are &lt;em&gt;not yet &lt;/em&gt;competent on the material. &lt;strong&gt;One &lt;/strong&gt;retake on any quiz or test is allowed; this lets you raise your grade to a B if you demonstrate competence on the retake. Retakes must be completed within three weeks of the original date, but in any case before the last week of the quarter. Weston policy does not permit carrying over work from one quarter to the next, except in cases of illness or other emergencies.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;There will be no exam. Your course grade will be the average of the two quarter grades.&lt;br&gt;
		&lt;/p&gt; --&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important.
If you&amp;#8217;re absent,
you&amp;#8217;re still responsible for any material missed!
Make up the work ASAP;
find out what we did in class by calling a classmate, or by sending email to your teacher,
or by seeing your teacher in school as soon as you return.
You need to make up any missed tests or quizzes right away.
If you absolutely must arrive at class late or leave early, do so as rarely as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
		
&lt;p&gt;In addition to your simple presence in class,
you will need to participate actively in two different ways.
First, of course, you must listen carefully, take the work seriously,
do all assigned work in class, and contribute whenever there are discussions or group work.
Second, you should sometimes volunteer to answer questions.
Whether you volunteer or not, you will be called on from time to time anyway, and occasional presentations are a required part of the course.&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;h2&gt;Online &amp;#147;Textbooks&amp;#148;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howstuffworks.com&quot;&gt;How Stuff Works&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3schools.com/&quot;&gt;W3Schools&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://diwww.epfl.ch/mantra/aeonline/course/&quot;&gt;The Analytical Engine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.hws.edu/TMCM/java/index.html&quot;&gt;The Most Complex Machine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.intel.com/museum/onlineexhibits.htm&quot;&gt;Intel Museum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hitmill.com/computers/computerhx1.html&quot;&gt;History of Computers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Online Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.filemaker.com/downloads/pdf/fm7_tutorial.pdf&quot;&gt;Official FileMaker tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fentonjones.com/FM101.html&quot;&gt;FileMaker 101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dwaynewright.com/afa/articles.html&quot;&gt;FileMaker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fgcu.edu/support/office2000/excel/&quot;&gt;Excel&lt;/a&gt; (Florida Gulf Coast Univ.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usd.edu/trio/tut/excel/&quot;&gt;Excel&lt;/a&gt; (Univ. of South Dakota)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://catb.org/~esr/jargon/html/index.html&quot;&gt;The Jargon File&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.w3schools.com/html/default.asp&quot;&gt;HTML Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.php.net/manual/en/tutorial.php&quot;&gt;PHP Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rochester.edu/IT/web/WebHelp/mysql/index.html&quot;&gt;MySQL Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Logic Gates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://isweb.redwoods.cc.ca.us/INSTRUCT/CalderwoodD/diglogic&quot;&gt;Introduction to Logic Gates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.autoshop101.com/trainmodules/logicgate/101.html&quot;&gt;Digital Logic Circuits&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stagecast.com/cgi-bin/templator.cgi?PAGE=Business/sims/LOGICGATESQUIZ&quot;&gt;Logic Gates with Quiz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.hws.edu/TMCM/java/labs/xLogicCircuitsLab1.html&quot;&gt;Logic Circuits Lab&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.d-project.com/simcir/index.html&quot;&gt;Logic Gates Applet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.turing.org.uk/turing/scrapbook/test.html&quot;&gt;The Turing Test&lt;/a&gt; (1950)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.psych.utoronto.ca/~reingold/courses/ai/turing.html&quot;&gt;More on the Turing Test&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.loebner.net/Prizef/loebner-prize.html&quot;&gt;The Loebner Prize&lt;/a&gt; for Turing Test competitors (1991)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stanford.edu/group/SHR/4-2/text/dialogues.html&quot;&gt;Dialogues with colorful personalities of early AI&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.a-i.com//&quot;&gt;AI Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.simonlaven.com/&quot;&gt;Chatterbots&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jabberwacky.com&quot;&gt;Jabberwacky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pandorabots.com/pandora/talk?botid=f5d922d97e345aa1&quot;&gt;ALICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://lcamtuf.coredump.cx/catty.shtml&quot;&gt;Catty&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newweb.net/cgi-bin/yeti/yeticgi.pl&quot;&gt;Yeti&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.zabaware.com/webhal&quot;&gt;Web Hal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">336</column>
            <column name="full_name">Computer Science: Introduction to Programming</column>
            <column name="short_name">Comp Sci: Intro Prog</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">CSIP</column>
            <column name="semesters">1</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">3</column>
            <column name="description">This course is intended for students who want an in-depth introduction
to computer programming. The course
will prepare students who want to go on to take Advanced Placement Computer Science
(APCS), as well as those who do not intend to take APCS later on. Students learn to design,
write, and test computer programs, using the DrScheme programming language.
Course topics include design recipes,
algorithms,
procedures, functions, variables and data types, simple and compound data structures, recursion, and debugging.</column>
            <column name="info">	&lt;h2&gt;Computer Science: Intro to Programming&lt;br&gt;
(Course 336)&lt;/h2&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Course Description:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This course is intended for students who want an in-depth introduction
to computer programming. Students learn to design,
write, and test computer programs, using the Python programming language.
Course topics include design recipes,
algorithms,
procedures, functions, variables and data types, simple and compound data structures, recursion, and debugging. The course
will prepare students for Advanced Placement Computer Science (Course 381).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Themes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design recipes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Functions and variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recursion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data definitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Student Outcomes:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will&amp;#133;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of the design recipe by writing programs including purpose, contract, test cases,
function header and body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of function composition by writing function definitions that compose
other functions.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of compound data by writing functions that
construct and decompose lists and structures, and by showing when to use which form of compound data.&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of computer graphics by drawing and animating images.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;demonstrate their understanding of designing and coding a substantial program by completing a guided project. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Course Content:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;b&gt;Topic 1, Functions Using Simple Data&lt;/b&gt;, students learn the fundamental design recipe and how to apply it
to writing and composing functions that consume and produce simple data, using variables and conditionals. Data types include numbers, images, strings, symbols, and booleans. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;b&gt;Topic 2, Functions Using Compound Data&lt;/b&gt;, students learn to define and apply a variety of compound data
types, including structures, unions, and lists. Iteration and recursion are introduced and used extensively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;b&gt;Topic 3, Applications and Mixed Data&lt;/b&gt;, students extend their use of compound data and apply their
knowledge to the task of writing a video game or other substantial application.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Materials:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbookproject.net/thinkcs/python/english2e/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How to Think Like a Computer Scientist &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;written by Jeffrey Elkner, Allen B. Downey, and Chris Meyers. &lt;br&gt;; supplemented by teacher-written materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software:  Python &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org&quot;&gt;http://www.python.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/gabrinerd/csip/CourseRequirementsGrading.html&quot;&gt;Course Requirements and Grading&lt;/a&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/download/releases/2.5.4/&quot;&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;http://pygame.org/download.shtml&quot;&gt;Pygame 2.5 msi installer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Download &lt;a href=&quot;http://wingware.com/pub/wingide-101/3.2.13/wingide-101-3.2.13-1.exe&quot;&gt;Wing IDE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.openbookproject.net/thinkcs/python/english2e/&quot;&gt;Online Textbook&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.python.org/tutorial/index.html&quot;&gt;Python Tutorial&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.python.org/reference/index.html&quot;&gt;Python Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.python.org/dev/peps/pep-0008/&quot;&gt;Python Style Guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/gabrinerd/csip/text2graphics.py&quot;&gt;Putting text on graphics example&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">341</column>
            <column name="full_name">Honors Precalculus</column>
            <column name="short_name">Honors Precalculus</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Hon Precalc</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">Trigonometry and its applications, conic sections, polynomials, complex numbers and polar coordinates, sequences and series, limits, fractals, and mathematical induction are some of the topics studied. Students will use graphing calculators regularly in this course as well as a variety of computer software. This course is a recommended prerequisite for any student considering enrollment in AB or BC Calculus (Course 361 or 371).</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;p&gt;Honors Precalculus deepens and broadens students&amp;#146; previous mathematical work. Major topics include trigonometry and its applications, polynomials, complex numbers, polar coordinates, sequences and series, limits, fractals, and mathematical induction. Computer programming is integrated into the mathematical work throughout the course, as are graphing calculators. There is a careful balance between mathematical theory and its application to many endeavors, such as navigation, economics, fractals, chaos, and the physics of motion, light, and sound. In all these contexts, students are expected to work hard to develop and demonstrate skills and concepts at an honors level.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;There are three major units during the year:&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit 1 &lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8212; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; Expanding Trigonometry&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8212; consists of four related modules:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first module focuses on solving triangles, starting with a review of the trigonometry of right triangles and moving on to all triangles &amp;#8212; with a point of view that considers sine, cosine, and tangent to be functions rather than mere  ratios &amp;#8212; including the Law of Cosines and Law of Sines.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second module develops the trig functions as wrapping functions, develops the inverse trig functions, studies polar graphing, and explores sinusoidal modeling of real-world periodic phenomena, especially music.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The third module introduces the reciprocal trig functions and incorporates trigonometric equations and identities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The fourth module applies trigonometry as it introduces complex numbers along with vectors and polar coordinates.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit 2&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8212; &lt;em&gt;Iteration and Recursion&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8212; explores many important ideas in mathematics. These range from the abstractions of mathematical induction to the practical applications of fractals and chaos theory. Sequences and iteration of functions are included in the unit.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unit 3&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;#8212; &lt;em&gt;Polynomials &amp; Numbers&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8212; deepens the students&amp;#146; experience in algebra and uses it to make sense of our numeration system.
Polynomial functions and conic sections have many implications both in mathematical theory and in applications, ranging from the binomial theorem to the physics of parabolic headlights and elliptical rooms.
Sequences, series, sigma notation, rational functions, and limits of sequences are explored.
The unit concludes with a study of limits of functions as an introduction to calculus.&lt;/p&gt;
		</column>
            <column name="policies">			&lt;h2&gt;Supplies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend that you use a well-organized 3-ring binder for all class notes, homework, returned tests and quizzes, and handouts.
If you wish to take notes in a spiral or perfect-bound notebook, you are welcome to do so &amp;#8212; but you should still have a 3-ring binder for handouts and for material that has been returned to you.
We have found that it is usually impossible to remain organized if you use folders for this purpose,
but that&amp;#8217;s up to you.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will also need pencils, erasers, lined paper, graph paper, and a graphing calculator. You may use any graphing calculator, but the TI-83 (or TI-83 Plus or TI-84) is recommended and will be used for class demonstrations.&lt;/p&gt;

		&lt;p&gt;While you aren&amp;#146;t actually &lt;i&gt;required &lt;/i&gt;to have a computer at home, you probably do have one. It will be extremely useful throughout the year, and will save you from needing to go to computer labs at school to do homework during or after the school day.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;h2&gt;Homework&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Homework is usually assigned four or five times in every eight-day cycle. To receive full credit, you must have your completed assignment with you &lt;em&gt;at the beginning of class&lt;/em&gt; on the day on which it is due. &lt;strong&gt;You must also show detailed work for all problems&lt;/strong&gt;, even when you were not successful. If you can&amp;#146;t solve a problem, record your attempts.
		
		&lt;p&gt;Working together on problems is allowed and encouraged. However, except in the most straightforward cases each student&amp;#146;s solution should look different, even when the answers are the same. Solutions that are identical may not be given credit. By this point you should know the difference between cooperation and cheating, and you should know how to work with others in an appropriate way without taking credit for their work. If you &lt;i&gt;do &lt;/i&gt;work with someone else, it is essential that you clearly indicate the name of the person(s) with whom you worked.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;Late homework will be accepted for half-credit if you hand it in by the beginning of the next class after the one when it was due &amp;#8212; provided it shows sincere effort and full work on all problems.		
		
		&lt;p&gt;Do your homework carefully and promptly. Include the date, your name, and the assignment
number. (This sounds trivial, but it isn&amp;#146;t. Without assignment numbers, it is difficult or impossible to find earlier assignments when it&amp;#146;s necessary to refer to them.) Write the entire problem
down, or at least show enough of it so you, your classmates, and your teacher can tell what the problem was!

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#146;t crowd your work. When you have a handout, or you&amp;#146;ve printed out your own copy of an assignment, you should treat that merely as a list of questions, not as a location for writing your solutions, except where ample space has been provided for your work! &lt;strong&gt;Write the solutions on a separate sheet of paper that you are prepared to hand in, and then keep it in your notebook. &lt;/strong&gt;Always do a thorough job. Sincere effort on homework assignments is, of course, essential to success in any course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all cases you must show your work! Answers are a penny a pound &amp;#8212; essentially worthless. It&amp;#146;s only the &lt;b&gt;process&lt;/b&gt; that will be of value to you: you&amp;#146;re
extremely unlikely to come across the exact same problem again, so you
need to be able to think and to communicate your thoughts.

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you&amp;#146;ll be unable to complete a solution. (Perhaps from
time to time you&amp;#146;ll even feel unable to &lt;em&gt;begin&lt;/em&gt; solving a problem successfully.) In such cases you still need to communicate your thoughts and your attempts; your teacher won&amp;#146;t want to see big white spaces instead of a solution. Come to class with a clear list of any questions you have about the homework problems; they may or may not be answered right away, so be sure that you can still find the list on subsequent days.

		&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Tests &amp; Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All tests will be announced well in advance, so you will have time to study. Each test will contain one part in which you may use both your calculator and a 3&quot;-by-5&quot; notecard, followed by a calculator-free and note-free part.

&lt;p&gt;Quizzes will &lt;em&gt;not &lt;/em&gt;be announced in advance, but you may usually use notes when taking a quiz. &lt;!-- These must be &lt;em&gt;your own notes&lt;/em&gt; &amp;#8212; not material from the text. Homework solutions that &lt;i&gt;you &lt;/i&gt;have written count as your own notes, but explanatory material that may be given out as part of an assignment does not. In other words, you may use your own work, not someone else&amp;#146;s. --&gt; Calculators may or may not be allowed
on quizzes, depending on the subject matter.

&lt;p&gt;You will receive two grades on each test or quiz: a &lt;b&gt;raw score&lt;/b&gt; and an &lt;b&gt;adjusted score&lt;/b&gt;. Adjusted scores are made by assessment of competence, not by arbitrary scaling or grading on a curve. Excellent work earns a 90 or higher, competent work an 80 or higher. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To earn an adjusted score of 90 or higher on a test or quiz, you must do an excellent job the first time you take it. But you can have a second chance to earn an 83 by learning the material later in the term. If you get below an adjusted score of 83 on a test or quiz, you are considered to have &amp;#147;not yet earned a B.&amp;#8221; You will have the opportunity &amp;#8212; which you are strongly urged to accept! &amp;#8212; to relearn any material on which you were not yet competent. You have two ways in which you may subsequently demonstrate your newly acquired competence:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;successfully solving problems on the next regularly scheduled test &lt;i&gt;if &lt;/i&gt;it covers the same skills and concepts as the quiz on which you earned below a B, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;meeting with your teacher to show that you have relearned the material, and then scheduling an appointment to take a new version of the test or quiz.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;

One retake per test or quiz is allowed.
The adjusted score on the original version will be multiplied by 1/3, the adjusted score on the retake by 2/3, and the two results added together, to a maximum of 83. (Note, however, that Weston High School&amp;#146;s grading policy does not permit carrying over work from one term to the next. Also, &lt;i&gt;retakes will not normally be permitted during the last week of any term, nor after the final exam.&lt;/i&gt;)

		&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;h2&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Your grade for the quarter will be computed as a weighted average of tests, quizzes, homework, projects, and class participation. Each test will be weighted as 100 points. Quizzes may vary, but will typically be weighted as 40 points or so. In a term with a major project, the project will be weighted as 80 points. Effort and success on class and homework problems may contribute up to 40 points during a quarter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will receive a quarter grade of A (or A-) if your overall average is at least 93 (or 90) &lt;em&gt;&lt;b&gt;and&lt;/b&gt; &lt;/em&gt;your test-and-quiz average is also at least a 90. You will receive a B (with a + or &amp;ndash; if appropriate) if your overall average is at least an 80. (Note that this means that an excellent job on homework or a project could be sufficient to raise your grade from, say, a C+ to a B&amp;ndash;, or even from an A- to an A, but not from a B+ to an A&amp;ndash;.)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final exam counts as 10%, and each quarter as 22.5%, toward your grade for the year.
&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;h2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Regular attendance is important and is expected of everyone. If you&amp;#146;re absent, you&amp;#146;re still responsible for any material missed! Make up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by calling a classmate, or by sending email to your teacher, or by seeing your teacher in school as soon as you return. You must make up any missed tests or quizzes right away. If you absolutely must arrive at class late or leave early, do so as rarely as possible.
		
		&lt;p&gt;In addition to your simple presence in class, you are required to participate actively in two different ways. First, of course, you must listen carefully, take the work seriously, do all assigned work in class, and contribute whenever there is group work. Second, you should sometimes volunteer to answer questions or demonstrate solutions. If you do not, you will be called on from time to time anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
		
		&lt;p&gt;The most important rule to follow in class is this: &lt;font color=&quot;#FF0000&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First, do no harm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/font&gt;. In other words, don&amp;#146;t interfere with your classmates&amp;#146; ability to learn. The second rule is to commit yourself to a serious attitude and do the work that&amp;#146;s expected of you in and out of class. The third rule is to participate actively in the Honors Precalculus community by helping your classmates learn.	&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;br&gt;

</column>
            <column name="resources">
&lt;h2&gt;Links&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Online texts:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opentextbookstore.com/precalc/1.2/Precalc.pdf&quot;&gt;Precalculus: An Investigation of Functions, by Lippman and Rasmussen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://stitz-zeager.com/Precalculus/Stitz_Zeager_Open_Source_Precalculus_files/SPreCalc07152011.pdf&quot;&gt;Precalculus, by Stitz and Zeager&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mecmath.net/trig/trigbook.pdf&quot;&gt;Trigonometry, by Corral&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/prerequisites.pdf&quot;&gt;Prerequisites: skills and practice problems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Fractal classwork on the Web:
		&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://tabish.freeshell.org/physics/fractal/frac.html&quot;&gt;Zoom in on Sierpinski&amp;#8217;s Triangle!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://agutie.homestead.com/files/Puzzle_Sierpinski_Machu.htm;&gt;The Sierpinski Puzzle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/fractured/worksheet.html&quot;&gt;Fractured Pictures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.rice.edu/~lanius/frac/koch.html&quot;&gt;Koch Snowflake&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://polymer.bu.edu/java&quot;&gt;BU Polymer Center Applets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/applets&quot;&gt;BU DYSYS Applets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/explorer/page1.html&quot;&gt; Mandelbrot Set Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/applets/Quadr.html&quot;&gt; Julia/Mandelbrot Explorer&lt;/a&gt; (The Quadratic Map)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/TwoVariableFunction&quot;&gt;Shodor Two Variable Function Pump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/JuliaSets&quot;&gt;Shodor Julia Set Applet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/applets/JuliaIteration.html&quot;&gt;Mandelbrot/Julia Applet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://polymer.bu.edu/ogaf/&quot;&gt;Exploring Patterns in Nature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mazeworks.com/hanoi/&quot;&gt;Interactive Tower of Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.rice.edu/~lanius/fractals/dim.html&quot;&gt;Fractal Dimension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.math.vt.edu/people/hoggard/FracGeomReport/node5.html&quot;&gt;Fractal Dimension: Some Common Examples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cs.cornell.edu/Courses/cs312/2000fa/handouts/fractals.html&quot;&gt;Mathematical Interpretation of Fractal Dimension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/fracdim/what.html&quot;&gt;Shodor Fractal Dimension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cut-the-knot.org/do_you_know/dimension.shtml&quot;&gt;Fractal Curves and Dimension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://physicsweb.org/articles/news/3/6/3/1&quot;&gt;Fractals determine date of paintings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://plus.maths.org/issue9/news/pollock/&quot;&gt;Jackson&amp;#8217;s Fractals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.phys.unsw.edu.au/PHYSICS_!/FRACTAL_EXPRESSIONISM/fractal_taylor.html&quot;&gt;Fractal Expressionism: Can Science Be Used To Further Our Understanding Of Art?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maa.org/mathland/mathtrek_9_20_99.html&quot;&gt;Jackson Pollock&amp;#8217;s Fractals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/trees2.html&quot;&gt;Fractal Trees in Scheme&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt; --&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shodor.org/interactivate/activities/TheChaosGame/&quot;&gt;Barnsley&amp;#8217;s Chaos Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/applets/chaos-game.html&quot;&gt;Devaney&amp;#8217;s Chaos Game&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fractalforums.com/&quot;&gt;Fractal Forums&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://classes.yale.edu/fractals/&quot;&gt;Yale Fractals Class&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/IFS.pdf&quot;&gt;Iterated Function Systems and Transformation Exercises&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/customer-images/B000K1KZHM/ref=cm_ciu_pdp_images_all/002-8116863-2875202#gallery&quot;&gt;An image that is (surprisingly) created entirely with fractals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/fractal-iteration-project/project-description.html&quot;&gt;Fractal Project Description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/fractal-iteration-project/rubric.pdf&quot;&gt;Fractal Project Rubric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://home.windstream.net/okrebs/&quot;&gt;OJK&amp;#146;s precalculus page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Practice &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.saab.org/mathdrills/factor.cgi&quot;&gt;factoring polynomials&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You really don&amp;#8217;t want to memorize the &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetmath.org/?op=getobj&amp;from=objects&amp;id=1407&quot;&gt;cubic formula&lt;/a&gt;; you especially don&amp;#8217;t want to memorize the &lt;a href=&quot;http://planetmath.org/?op=getobj&amp;from=objects&amp;name=QuarticFormula&quot;&gt;quartic formula&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You may download the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ticalc.org/archives/files/fileinfo/84/8442.html&quot;&gt;TI-83 emulator&lt;/a&gt; as long as you legally own a TI-83 or TI-83+ calculator.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.research.att.com/~njas/sequences/&quot;&gt;Encyclopedia of Integer Sequences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://matti.usu.edu/grapher/&quot;&gt;Matti Grapher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathopenref.com/cubicexplorer.html&quot;&gt;Cubic Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;li&gt;There are a lot of interesting pages about math (and many other subjects) at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jimloy.com&quot;&gt;Jim Loy's&lt;/a&gt; website. If you want to go directly to the math pages and ignore the other material, just append &lt;b&gt;/math/math.htm&lt;/b&gt; to the URL.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.analyzemath.com/free_graph_paper/free_graph_paper.html&quot;&gt;Download blank graph paper&lt;/a&gt; of various shapes and sizes (including polar), and print out as much as you need.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mac.softpedia.com/progDownload/MacCRO-X-Download-30776.html&quot;&gt;Mac Oscilloscope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rogertaylor.com/reference/Mathsongsing-a-long.pdf&quot;&gt;Math Songs&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;this site may still be broken&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;
Music &amp; Trig&lt;/b&gt; from the EECS 20 course at UC Berkeley
(except for the last two links in this list):&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/eecs20&quot;&gt;Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/eecs20/sidebars/hertz&quot;&gt;Frequencies and Sinusoidal Functions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/eecs20/week8/frequencylive.html&quot;&gt;Frequency Decomposition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/eecs20/week8/scale.html&quot;&gt;Musical Scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ptolemy.eecs.berkeley.edu/eecs20/week8/phase.html&quot;&gt;Phase&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://webcast.berkeley.edu/courses/archive.php?seriesid= 1906978195&quot;&gt;Lectures&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;try October 14 and 19&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And closely related is &lt;a href=&quot;http://hyperphysics.phy-astr.gsu.edu/hbase/sound/earsens.html&quot;&gt;this page&lt;/a&gt; on the physics and anatomy of the sensitivity of the human ear. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vibrationdata.com/piano.htm&quot;&gt;Piano frequencies and overtones&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;There&amp;#146;s no need to travel all the way to Latvia. Right from the comfort of your own room you can travel along &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.liis.lv/NMS/bw03&quot;&gt;the Baltic Way&lt;/a&gt; to challenge yourself with the world&amp;#146;s best math competition.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;

	
		
		&lt;h2&gt;Calendar&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fourth test of the year
will be held on Tuesday, 1/8.
You may use a calculator and &lt;i&gt;one &lt;/i&gt;3&quot;-by-5&quot; notecard during part of the test.&lt;!-- 
Here are some &lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/final-exam-review.pdf &quot;&gt;practice problems&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/teachers/davidsonl/precalch/final-exam-review-2012-solutions.pdf &quot;&gt;solutions thereto&lt;/a&gt;. --&gt;
&lt;!--Topics will be announced on or before 12/8.  --&gt;
 You will be well-prepared if you can do the following: 
&lt;!--  The structure of the exam is as follows:
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 120%; text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Part A&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solve a trig equation (8 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;prove a trig identity (8 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a sinusoidal modeling problem (12 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a conics problem (8 points)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 120%; text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Part B&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;

&lt;li&gt;a polynomial graph (8 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a problem with sums and limits (6 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a rational function problem (8 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a mathematical induction proof (8 points)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a complex number problem (6 points)&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;  
			


&lt;li&gt;Use the appropriate form of a &lt;!-- vector or  --&gt;complex number for any particular problem.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; 
			
&lt;li&gt;Represent complex numbers in graphs, polar form,&lt;!--  &lt;i&gt;cis &lt;/i&gt;form, --&gt; and rectangular form.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Use Newton&amp;#8217;s Method to find roots of complex numbers.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
	
&lt;li&gt;Without the aid of a calculator, perform basic arithmetic and algebra (sums, differences, products, quotients, powers, and roots) on complex numbers, including appropriate use of conjugates.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;Solve quadratic equations with complex as well as real solutions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Understand how to plot graphs of equations using polar coordinates.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; 

 &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Find the orbit of a complex number for a given function, and thereby determine whether that seed is a prisoner or an escapee and specifically what its fate is.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;

&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Find fixed points and periods for iteration for a function of a complex number.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;
Sketch any iteration of an unfamiliar geometric fractal for which you are given the initiator (seed) and generator (rule for iterating), and find its perimeter and area if they are based on simple geometry.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;
Find the fractal dimension for any classical fractal.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
 			 --&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Convert between radians and degrees (in both directions).&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Determine whether a given point is in a given function&amp;#146;s Filled Julia Set.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
 			
&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #FF0000;&quot;&gt;Determine whether a given point is in the Mandelbrot Set and/or in a given function&amp;#146;s Julia Set,
and interpret the connection between the two.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;

&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Know and apply the sine, cosine, and tangent functions, from the original SOH-CAH-TOA definitions through the expansion to obtuse angles to the unit circle definitions.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Compute values and sketch graphs of wrapping functions for any geometric object.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;


&lt;!--&lt;li&gt; &lt;i&gt;Notecard section only&lt;/i&gt;: Recall the formulas for sine and cosine of sums of
angles; recall or efficiently derive the formulas for the tangent
of a sum and  the differences of angles and double angle formulas for sine,
cosine, and tangent; apply all of these.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Sketch graphs of the sums and products of functions.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;li&gt;Find sides, angles, and all trigonometric functions for angles that are multiples of &amp;pi;/6 and &amp;pi;/4 (30&amp;deg; and 45&amp;deg;) without a calculator.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Find the sine, cosine, tangent, secant, cosecant, and cotangent of any input, paying proper attention to domains and ranges.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
			 
&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Find the values of the inverse trig functions for all inputs in their domains, and correctly use the limited ranges of the arcsine, arccosine,
and arctangent functions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
			
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Sketch graphs of all six trig functions and the inverses of sin, cos, and tan.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
				
 &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Interpret periodic functions as wrapping functions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;   

&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Construct and apply sinusoidal models of periodic phenomena with appropriate periods, amplitudes, vertical shifts, and horizontal shifts.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
 --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Construct and interpret graphs of musical tones, finding and using frequencies and amplitudes as needed.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
&lt;!-- 
 &lt;li&gt;Find and apply frequencies of notes in any given equal-tempered scale (there&amp;#8217;s no need to memorize any particular frequency or any particular scale).&lt;br /&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;--&gt;
	
&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Perform appropriate transformations of equations in order to translate, reflect, and stretch their graphs.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
  
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Solve trigonometric equations using sin, cos, and tan.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Solve trigonometric equations using sin, cos, tan, sec, csc, and cot.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

 &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Use and prove trig identities.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;

 &lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Understand and apply domain restrictions in both of these situations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

&lt;!--   &lt;li&gt;Use the Law of Sines and Law of Cosines appropriately to solve triangles.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
&lt;!-- 			
 &lt;li&gt;Determine the properties of a graph of a polynomial  or rational function from its coefficients and exponents, and vice versa. Properties include rising vs. falling, number and location of real zeros and their multiplicities, number of turning points,  &lt;i&gt;x- &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;y-&lt;/i&gt;intercepts, and touching vs. crossing the &lt;i&gt;x-&lt;/i&gt;axis, holes (undefined points), asymptotes, and limits. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  
			
  &lt;li&gt;Factor and divide polynomials.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
			
&lt;li&gt;Use the Binomial Theorem.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;

&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Produce the standard and graphing forms of an equation from the horizontally or vertically oriented graph &amp;#8212; and vice versa &amp;#8212; for any conic section and determine the type of conic, vertices, foci, major and minor axes,  directrix (parabola only), and asymptotes (hyperbola only).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;    --&gt;
			
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Apply the locus definitions and properties of conic sections to real-world situations.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
			
&lt;!--   &lt;li&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #FF0000;&quot;&gt;Determine whether a fraction repeats or terminates when written as a &amp;#147;decimal&amp;#148; in any base.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;   --&gt;
			
		&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Use Del Ferro&amp;#8217;s Method to solve cubics (with a notecard).&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
			
&lt;!--   &lt;li&gt;Write explicit and recursive definitions for sequences and series,
including use of sigma notation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 

 &lt;li&gt;Find terms of arithmetic or geometric sequences and series from explicit or recursive definitions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;  

 &lt;li&gt;Find sums of finite series from explicit or recursive definitions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  
			
 &lt;li&gt;Find limits of infinite sequences, series, and functions.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
			
&lt;!--  &lt;li&gt;Find vertical, horizontal, and slant asymptotes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  --&gt;
		
&lt;!--   &lt;li&gt;Prove that a number is rational or irrational, as the case may be.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;   --&gt; 

&lt;!-- 		&lt;li&gt;Prove the irrationality of certain radicals.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;
		
&lt;!-- &lt;li&gt;Prove theorems by mathematical induction.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt; --&gt;

  &lt;li&gt;Explain all of the above clearly and accurately.&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;/ol&gt; 
</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">342</column>
            <column name="full_name">Precalculus, Part One</column>
            <column name="short_name">Precalc, Part I</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Precalc I</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">The content of this course includes trigonometry, complex numbers, polynomials, and probability. Students will be expected to become proficient in the application of technology to the study of mathematics.  They will use graphing calculators regularly throughout the course and also a variety of computer packages as needed. Applications of mathematics will be emphasized throughout the course. Successful completion of the course will prepare students for a college-level discrete mathematics &lt;i&gt;or &lt;/i&gt;precalculus course.  In combination with Precalculus, Part Two, with Statistics (Course 352) or with additional summer work, students will be prepared for calculus.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;h2&gt;Themes:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Provide students with an appreciation of the importance of mathematics in society by emphasizing mathematical applications and models.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Graphing technology is used to compare the behaviors of functions within different function families.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;li&gt;Transformations are developed as a tool for creating functions with desired properties.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Topics are approached by exploring different representations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Course Content: &lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;First Quarter: Circle and Triangle Trigonometry&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;	Angles and Their Measure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;	Unit Circle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 	Properties and graphs of the Trigonometric Functions &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 	Right Triangle Trigonometry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 	The Inverse Trigonometric Functions&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;li&gt; 	Trigonometric Equations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 	Create different representations of trigonometric functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; 	Model real world situations with periodic functions.&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Second Quarter:  Complex Numbers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduction of complex numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploration of fractals using the Julia set and Mandelbrot set.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Third Quarter:  Polynomial Functions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze polynomials both graphically and algebraically in order to understand the behaviors of maxima, minima, roots, and long term behavior. &lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Solve polynomial equations and explore situations that can be modeled using polynomial equations.  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;br&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fourth Quarter:  Probability&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Counting Techniques &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combinations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permutations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conditional Probability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quarterly Grades&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;  
75% of your grade will come from a weighted average of quizzes, tests and projects.		
25% will come from participation, preparation and homework completion according to your teacher
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quizzes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Quizzes can be announced or unannounced.  You may use your binder for unannounced quizzes if you brought it to class.   There are no retakes on quizzes. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tests&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Tests are always announced.  Tests will be worth approximately twice as much as a quiz.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Test Retakes&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If you score below an 83%, you may retake the test.  Before you are allowed to retake the test, you need to complete corrections on the original test, new practice problems and homework assignments from the unit.   
Your final test score will be calculated by  2/3 * score on retake    +    1/3*original score.  
The highest grade you may bring your final test grade up to is an 83%.

The use of notecards on quizzes and tests will depend on the material.  
It is at the discretion of the teacher. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Projects&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;  
Projects assigned during the course of the year will be worth one, two or three quizzes, depending on the size and difficulty of the project. 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Semester grades&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;  
Semester grades are computed by averaging the numerical grades for two quarters.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Year grades&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The final exam will be worth 10% of your year grade.  The other 90% will come from the average of the four quarterly grades.  
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Seniors&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;br&gt;  The fourth quarter will be weighted half as much as any other quarter.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;h3&gt;Online Text Book&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.keymath.com/PreCalc2&quot;&gt;
http://www.keymath.com/PreCalc2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Ask your teacher for the ClassPass

&lt;h3&gt;Online Graphers:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href = &quot;http://matti.usu.edu/grapher&quot;&gt;Up to three graphs at once&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href = &quot;http://math.hws.edu/javamath/basic_applets/GraphApplet3.html&quot;&gt;One graph with good trace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href = &quot;http://math.hws.edu/javamath/basic_applets/SliderGraph.html&quot;&gt;One graph with sliders for constants&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href = &quot;http://www.mathgv.com/&quot;&gt;More powerful downloadable grapher can do multiple functions in 2 and 3 dimensions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Web Resources&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.clarku.edu/~djoyce/trig/&quot;&gt;Dave's Trigonometry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://zebu.uoregon.edu/~probs/bas/trig/people/node4.html&quot;&gt;Curvature of the earth problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://sodaplay.com/creators/ed/items/daintywalker&quot; title=&quot;open this item on sodaplay.com&quot;&gt; Soda Play Constructor&lt;img src=&quot;http://sodaplay.com/creators/ed/items/daintywalker.png&quot; width=&quot;120&quot; height=&quot;80&quot; alt=&quot;daintywalker&quot; /&gt;  &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.themathpage.com/aTrig/trigonometry.htm&quot;&gt;The Math Page: Topics in Trig&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nlvm.usu.edu/en/nav/frames_asid_189_g_4_t_2.html&quot;&gt;Algebra Tiles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://archives.math.utk.edu/visual.calculus/0/shifting.7/index.html&quot;&gt;Function Transformation Quiz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mandelbrot and Julia Set Resources&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/explorer/page1.html&quot;&gt;
BU Mandelbrot Set Explorer Main Page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/applets/Quadr.html&quot;&gt;BU Quadratic Map Applet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://aleph0.clarku.edu/~djoyce/julia/explorer.html&quot;&gt;
Clark Univ. Mandelbrot and Julia Set Explorer (good for downloading images)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://math.bu.edu/DYSYS/FRACGEOM/FRACGEOM.html&quot;&gt;
Fractal Geometry of the Mandelbrot Set&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">343</column>
            <column name="full_name">Applied Discrete Math Concepts</column>
            <column name="short_name">App Discrete Math</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">ADMC</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course offers students who have successfully completed Algebra Two the opportunity to study the application of important mathematical concepts to real world issues and problems.  Students will gain a solid understanding of  fundamental mathematical ideas by developing mathematical models and applying technology while using these models for decision making.  The topics studied might include mathematical models for the study of traffic and the spread of gossip or disease, the use of probability and inferential statistics to make predictions from limited data, applied game theory, mathematical systems for modeling situations ranging from urban geography to political decision making, and numeracy including the history of mankind?s attempts to represent and store numeric data. Students may elect to take the course as a senior elective or as preparation for Course 342.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;HTML&gt;
&lt;!--This file created 12:14 PM  9/3/03 by Claris Home Page version 3.0--&gt;
&lt;HEAD&gt;
   &lt;META NAME=GENERATOR CONTENT=&quot;Claris Home Page 3.0&quot;&gt;
   &lt;X-CLARIS-WINDOW TOP=0 BOTTOM=603 LEFT=0 RIGHT=1012&gt;
   &lt;X-CLARIS-TAGVIEW MODE=minimal&gt;
&lt;/HEAD&gt;
&lt;BODY BGCOLOR=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;Applied Discrete Math Concepts (Course 343)&lt;/H1&gt;

&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;CENTER&gt;
               
 &lt;/CENTER&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;&lt;/BLOCKQUOTE&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Course Description:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;This course is for students who have successfully completed
Algebra Two but who are looking for an alternative to the abstraction and heavy
symbol manipulation of Pre-Calculus. (The course may also be taken by
seniors who have completed Pre-Calculus part 1 but do not wish to complete
their precalculus work by taking Pre-Calculus part 2.) The course emphasizes
the use of mathematics to model diverse real world situations in
order to assist in decision making. Students should leave the course
with an appreciation for the power and versatility of mathematics and
increased confidence in their ability to apply mathematics.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Themes:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;OL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;The applicability of a single mathematical model to a variety
   of situations.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Using mathematical models for decision making in both personal
   and professional settings.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Acquiring a useful set of mathematical &quot;reference points&quot; for
   understanding new information (examples: how large is a trillion?
   how significant is a 1 in 10,000 risk? How reliable are the
   results of a poll?)&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Communicating through mathematics - reading , writing and
   speaking mathematics.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Reflectiveness as a learner- exploring how one approaches new
   learning and what aspects assist or impede that learning.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Student Outcomes:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Students will&amp;#133;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;OL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;demonstrate an understanding that mathematics uses numbers and
   other symbols to describe abstractions of real world phenomena by
   using Game Theory to analyze a conflict situation from current
   events. (Benchmark Assessment)&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;demonstrate an understanding that a measurement has an implied
   precision and measures a given attribute by developing a variety
   of measurements of different magnitudes for the same attribute.
   (Benchmark Assessment)&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;improve their ability to assess and compare risks and be aware
   of some of the psychological factors that influence such
   assessments.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;demonstrate an understanding that mathematical measures can
   indicate how likely it is that results from a sample will apply to
   the population at large by using appropriate mathematics to
   describe the results from a sample poll or experiment. (Benchmark
   Assessment)&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;regularly assess their learning and problem solving
   approaches.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;demonstrate their understanding that representing selected
   parts of available information is an important problem solving
   tool by using a simulation of an abstract representation of
   localized behavior to predict global patterns and consequences.
   &lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Course Content:&lt;/H2&gt;





&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 1, Inferential Statistics&lt;/B&gt;, uses ideas of probability
and sampling to understand confidence intervals and what is meant by
the phrase &quot;statistically significant.&quot; Students will be able to
interpret and evaluate the results of public opinion polls and test
each other for evidence of ESP.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 2, Numeracy and Risk Analysis&lt;/B&gt;, assists students in acquiring useful
references for handling very large and very small quantities and
rates. Students will practice estimating quantities by both research
and common sense and will combine those estimates to obtain
approximate answers to questions such as &quot;How many cans of cat food
are opened in New York City in one year?&quot; They will explore various
ways of measuring and comparing risks and factors which influence a
person's decision to engage in risky behavior.  Students will also develop insight into why certain risks are overrated in our society compared to others that are underrated.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 3, Graph Theory&lt;/B&gt;, introduces students to important concepts in graph theory such as Eulerian Paths and Hamiltonian Paths, graph coloring and the four color theorem.  Students will learn how graph theory can model social networks, the spread of disease, as well as the structure of corporations. The attributes of each graph can have many important implications from the efficiency of interactions to the best way to prevent the spread of disease.  &lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 4, Queueing Theory and Optimization&lt;/B&gt;, allows students to develop strategies for modeling different types of lines. Students will learn which queueing discipline is most efficient and how to determine the number of servers needed for different customer frequencies.  Students will also learn how to predict the length of a line using Little's Law. Students will also use the Manhattan Metric to optimize efficiency for the location of ambulances, school districting lines, and location of trash collectors.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 5, Game Theory&lt;/B&gt;, offers students the opportunity to
learn a mathematical model which has wide application to conflict
situations. Students will determine payoffs for various strategies
and apply algebraic and graphical techniques to determine which
strategy or mixture of strategies will yield the best average payoff.
Analysis of particular games such as &quot;Chicken&quot; and &quot;the Prisoner's
Dilemma&quot; will enable students to discuss the power and limitations of
rational analysis when making decisions. The conflict situations
discussed will range from analysis of voting procedures to nuclear
deterrence, from honor systems to using weather forecasts, from board
games to deciding what locations to protect from terrorist
attack.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 6, Emergence&lt;/B&gt;, explores systems where
locally defined behavior applied to a large number of individuals
results in surprising patterns on a global scale. Students will use
the Net logo computer program to simulate events similar to traffic
jams and ant colonies.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Materials:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Texts: &lt;u&gt;For All Practical Purposes&lt;/u&gt;, written by a committee and
published by COMAP (Consortium for Mathematics and Its Applications)
sixth edition; &lt;u&gt;Workshop Statistics&lt;/u&gt;, written by Rossman, Chance and Oehsen, and published by Key College Publishing; supplemented extensively by teacher-written
materials.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Videos/film: COMAP's For All Practical Purposes video and a
variety of brief excerpts from movies demonstrating relevant
mathematical concepts.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Software: Spreadsheets, graphing software, Internet browsers, and Net Logo are all used in the
course.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Calculators: Students are required to use a graphing calculator,
preferably the TI-83.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Other Resources: Access to daily newspapers and recent periodicals
will assist the student in locating applications of the mathematical
decision making techniques being learned.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/BODY&gt;
&lt;/HTML&gt;</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;HTML&gt;
&lt;!--This file created 12:03 PM  9/3/03 by Claris Home Page version 3.0--&gt;
&lt;HEAD&gt;
   &lt;META NAME=GENERATOR CONTENT=&quot;Claris Home Page 3.0&quot;&gt;
   &lt;X-CLARIS-WINDOW TOP=0 BOTTOM=603 LEFT=0 RIGHT=1012&gt;
   &lt;X-CLARIS-TAGVIEW MODE=minimal&gt;
&lt;/HEAD&gt;
&lt;BODY BGCOLOR=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;&lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;B&gt;Course 343&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/CENTER&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;

&lt;H1&gt;&lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;B&gt;Applied Topics in Precalculus&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/CENTER&gt;&lt;/H1&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Supplies&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;You will need a well-organized notebook. Keep your class notes,
homework, handouts and returned quests, problems sets, and projects
in it or a folder that you have with you. Developing a system that
helps you keep your work organized will be a great support to your
learning.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;You will also need writing implements, lined and unlined paper,
graph paper, and a graphing calculator. You may use any graphing
calculator, but the TI-83 (in any of its varieties) is recommended
and will be used for class demonstrations. At home you will need a
ruler,  but we'll provide one if you need it in the
classroom.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;You will need to do certain assignments on a computer with
Internet access. If one is not available at home, be sure to leave
time to go to a computer lab at school during or after the school
day. Check the resources page to learn about useful computer programs
you can download.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Homework&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Homework will be posted on www.westonmath.org.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Your work at home will come in a number of different forms. You
will often have a nightly assignment. To participate fully in the
coming class and to be prepared for other activities associated with
the class, it is essential that you have your completed assignment
with you at the beginning of class on the day on which it is due. You
must show your work for all problems, even when you are not
successful. If you can't solve a problem, record your attempts.
Specifically, write down what part of a problem statement or what
step in the problem solution process made it difficult for you to go
on (i.e., pin down the cause of your stuckness- once you can
identify your obstacles, you will have a better chance of overcoming
them). Another reason to show all of your work is that it is the
process that will be of value to you in your future work: you are
extremely unlikely to come across the exact same problem again, so
you need to be able to think and to communicate your thoughts about
the structure of the problem and how you approached it. Your homework
will be a valuable resource for open-notebook quests (see below).&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Do your homework carefully and promptly. Include the date, your
name, the assignment, and the assignment number. (This sounds
trivial, but it isn't. Without assignment numbers, it is
difficult or impossible to find earlier assignments when it is
necessary to refer to them.) Write the entire problem down, or at
least show enough of it so you and the teacher can tell what the
problem was!&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Doing the reading is imperative. Occasionally you will be asked to
read a section prior to its being discussed in class. You must take
notes on the reading and record questions which you have at any point
while doing your work. Writing and reflecting while reading is an
important step toward becoming an independent learner. Focus not only
on the basic skills and definitions but also on their application in
various situations.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The most valuable problems are those you really work on. Some
problems from this course you'll want to try again the next day
- indeed, the most effective students spend a part of their
homework time revisiting past problems and trying to solve them (or
resolve them more efficiently or elegantly) using hints and ideas
presented in the last class.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;If you work on a problem whose answer is in the back of the book,
please check it (this is not cheating! It is part of doing your
homework) and show a second attempt for incorrect solutions.  For
problems without answers, consider how you can assess the correctness
of your work. You should come to class with specific questions about
problems.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Homework, class notes, etc. may be written in pen. The benefit of
using a pen is that you do not erase work that may turn out to be
worthwhile- that is, you keep a complete record of your thinking.
If you think work is incorrect, please put a single diagonal line
through it and try again (do not annihilate it).&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Tests&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Tests may not be announced in advance. This practice encourages
you to remain up-to-date in your work and actively and promptly
seeking help addressing any questions that you may have about a
topic. All tests will be cumulative. Tests will be open notebook
except for ideas that are sufficiently central to your learning that
you have been given notice to memorize them. An organized notebook
with good notes that is with you in class will serve you well.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Problem Sets&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;During each unit, you will receive a series of problem sets
(approximately one per 8 day cycle). You will work on a problem set
both in class and at home. Problem sets are designed to help you
reflect on the ideas that you have been studying, to practice
specific skills, and to solve problems that may require repeated
efforts. Take the time to read over a problem set the night that you
receive it, to identify which questions may take time to resolve, and
to give yourself the chance to work on them, take a break, and return
to them over a number of days. Unlike an exercise that is solved
quickly, such problems give your brain the chance to play with the
question during your breaks from it even when you are doing something
else (your brain can do more than one thing at a time). You may find
that challenges are more successfully faced through short repeated
visits than one long attempt. &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Problem sets are formal assignments that you will submit. They
should be written neatly and with full, clear explanations (even
where not explicitly requested). Write the solution for each problem
on a separate side of paper and staple all of your pages
together.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Class Participation&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Because this course focuses on making decisions and connecting
mathematics to your own personal and professional life, your
creativity, involvement, and openness to exploration is essential to
your own and your classmates' learning. Each student's
perspectives will enrich the discussions and contribute to the fun
and insight we can gain from these topics.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Class will provide you the opportunity to raise questions around
issues about which you are curious as well as about ideas that are
confusing you. Both types of questions are important and will serve
you and your peers. However, there may be problems that are not
satisfactorily addressed in class. Please arrange for extra help with
your teacher if you are not confident about your understanding of a
subject. These chances for individualized attention can make a great
difference in how much you benefit from our whole class discussions.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you are absent,
you are still responsible for any material missed. Please make up the
work as soon as possible and find out what we did in class by calling
a classmate, sending an email to your teacher, or by seeing your
teacher in school as soon as you return. Check www.westonmath.org for
the homework assignment. You must make up any missed quests right
away. If you know that you will be absent for a class or will have to
arrive late or leave early due to an appointment or other school
activity, please let your teachers know well in advance so that they
can help you to stay on track.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Please study the participation rubric so that you are clear about
the expectations.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Grading&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Your grade for the quarter will be computed as a weighted average
of quests and projects (50%), problem sets (40%), and class
participation (10%). Quests will be weighted the same, group projects
will count as 1.5 quests, and individual projects as 2 quests.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Striving for Understanding and Competence&lt;/B&gt; &lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;If you earn a grade lower than a B on a quest, you will have the
option to do extra preparation as determined by your teacher and then
take a new quest. You will be able to earn up to a grade of B with
this second effort. It is your responsibility to come for the extra
assignment, to do the work, and to submit it to your teacher for
approval. If the work is satisfactory, then a retest will be given
during your free time. You should consider coming for extra help, but
you may not take the retest on the same day as the help. Retakes must
be taken within two weeks of the original quest. Under certain
circumstances, your teacher may count work on a subsequent quest as
evidence of your progress in lieu of a separate retake. &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;If your work on a project reveals fundamental misunderstandings
with regard to the material, you may be given the opportunity to
submit a revised or second version of the project.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/BODY&gt;
&lt;/HTML&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1562958,00.html&quot;&gt;Why we worry about the wrong things risk appendix&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.time.com/time/magazine/article/0,9171,1562978-1,00.html&quot;&gt;Why we worry about the wrong things Article&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Graph Theory Links&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Try to create some 
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://bcs.whfreeman.com/fapp7e/content/cat_010/EulerCircuit.html&quot;&gt;Euler Circuits&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Take a short quiz to see if you understand the concept of &lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.flashandmath.com/mathlets/discrete/graphtheory/isomorphism.html&quot;&gt;Isomorphic Graphs&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
See if you can find the shortest path for the
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://bcs.whfreeman.com/fapp7e/content/cat_010/TSP_NN.html&quot;&gt;Traveling Salesman&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Practice some more
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://bcs.whfreeman.com/fapp7e/content/cat_010/GraphColoring.html&quot;&gt;graph coloring&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/P&gt;
Now see if you can
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://bcs.whfreeman.com/fapp7e/content/cat_010/Scheduling.html&quot;&gt; do some scheduling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Do the
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://primes.utm.edu/cgi-bin/caldwell/tutor/graph/index.html&quot;&gt;Graph Theory Tutorial part 1&lt;/a&gt; 

&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Try to take quizzes on
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://bcs.whfreeman.com/fapp7e/&quot;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Check out this &lt;a
HREF=&quot;http://www.cut-the-knot.org/Curriculum/Combinatorics/ColorGraph.shtml&quot;&gt; Graph Coloring Applet!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Try this version of the 
&lt;a
HREF=&quot;http://www.math.princeton.edu/math_alive/5/Lab1/BridgeChoices.html&quot;&gt;Bridge Problem&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Try to 
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://bcs.whfreeman.com/fapp7e/content/cat_010/Euler.html&quot;&gt;
Eulerize these graphs&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Play the
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.planarity.net/#&quot;&gt; Planarity Game!&lt;/a&gt; (Yes, you can download it free onto your iphone!)
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Other Links&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;
The fourth topic of the course is the study of decentralized potentially self-organizing systems.  Our primary tool is the NetLogo program and each student should take advantage of the free download (Download your copy &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://ccl.northwestern.edu/netlogo/download.shtml&quot;&gt; here &lt;/a&gt;)

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://moneycentral.msn.com/investor/calcs/n_expect/main.asp&quot;&gt;life expectancy calculator&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a
href=&quot;http://calculator.livingto100.com/calculator&quot;&gt;Living to 100 Calculator&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;P.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.northwesternmutual.com/learning-center/the-longevity-game.aspx&quot;&gt;The Longevity Game&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.msrs.state.mn.us/info/Age_Cal.htmls&quot;&gt;How these calculations are done&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kokogiak.com/megapenny/default.asp&quot;&gt;Click here to look at the megapenny project!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Here are some NetLogo files you will need:
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mclaughlinj/admc/BumperBasics-1.nlogo&quot;&gt;Bumperbasics&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mclaughlinj/admc/startingfile.nlogo&quot;&gt;Starting File&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mclaughlinj/admc/DesignYourOwnPath1.nlogo&quot;&gt;Design Your Own Path&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://ccl.northwestern.edu/netlogo/docs/&quot;&gt;Net Logo Online Resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
Watch the 
&lt;A
HREF= &quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hpHpBHJZQvU&quot;&gt;Slime Mold Video!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;teachers/mclaughlinj/admc/SamplingSim.ftm&quot;&gt;Fathom Activity&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.surveymonkey.com/s.aspx?sm=wDOhL8nHGWKO8NclxjQy6w_3d_3d&quot;&gt;Click Here to take election survey&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.stat.sc.edu/~west/javahtml/LetsMakeaDeal.html&quot;&gt;Monty Hall Simulation&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://veconlab.econ.virginia.edu/login.php&quot;&gt;Game Theory Games!&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.aflcio.org/unionshop/games/game_mancala.cfm&quot;&gt;Mancala&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://serendip.brynmawr.edu/playground/pd.html&quot;&gt;Prisoner's Dilemma Game&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;A
HREF=&quot;http://www.iterated-prisoners-dilemma.net/&quot;&gt;Repeated Prisoner's Dilemma&lt;/a&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">352</column>
            <column name="full_name">Precalculus, Part Two, with Statistics</column>
            <column name="short_name">Precalc, Part II</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Precalc II</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course provides a detailed study of precalculus and discrete mathematics topics. Included in the course are analysis of functions and limits as applied to rational, exponential, and trigonometric functions; recursion and mathematical induction; complex numbers; and polar coordinates.  Additional work may be done in logic, combinatorics, and with the concept of derivatives and  integrals. Successful completion of this course will provide a strong background for college-level work in calculus and other mathematics related courses in engineering and science programs.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H2&gt;Course Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precalculus, Part Two, is a combination of two one semester courses. The first semester is an introduction to calculus, and the second semester is an introduction to inferential statistics. Most students will take both semesters; however, those who are concurrently enrolled in AP Statistics will take only the first semester (introduction to calculus).  Successful completion of this course will provide a strong background for college level work in either calculus or statistics as well as and other mathematics related courses in engineering and science programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;First Semester Themes:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sequences, Series, and Limits&lt;/li&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Average and Instantaneous Rates of Change&lt;/li&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Derivative&lt;/li&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Areas Under a Curve and the Integral&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Second Semester Themes:&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describing Distributions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Densities and Normal Distributions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sampling Distributions and Estimation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;BR&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hypothesis Testing&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Student Outcomes Semester One:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will:
&lt;li&gt;1. 	Learn how to identify different types of sequences, such as linear, exponential, and quadratic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2. 	Learn how to find the sum of a finite number of terms from an arithmetic or a geometric sequence, and how to find the sum of an infinite number of terms from a geometric sequence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3. 	Learn how to determine the limits of sequences, series, and rational functions, if such limits exist.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4. 	Learn how to calculate average rates of change for functions over varying intervals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5. 	Learn how to use a limiting process to move from average rates of change to instantaneous rates of change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6. 	Become familiar with the idea of a derivative function and the relationship of this function to the instantaneous rate of change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7.          Learn how to calculate the area under a curve through a limiting process, and become familiar with the relationship of the area to the concept of the definite integral.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Student Outcomes Semester Two:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students will:
&lt;li&gt;1. 	Explore the concept of random sampling to a variety of different populations, developing the Central Limit Theorem as a result.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2. 	Calculate and interpret confidence intervals for a population mean from sample data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3. 	Conduct tests of significance for a population mean from sample data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4. 	Use the concepts of statistical inference to draw valid conclusions about a certain population.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5. 	Demonstrate an understanding of sampling distributions and the Central Limit Theorem by analyzing different arguments to determine which are valid. (Benchmark Assessment)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Course Content:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Precalculus2 will consist of two big units: an introduction to calculus, and an introduction to statistical inference. Each of these
topics builds on the knowledge you gained in your previous
mathematics courses, and requires you to use your current
mathematical knowledge on a daily basis. Our goals are to prepare you
for college-level work in mathematics (including calculus), as well
as to expose you to some of the mathematics you may see (and use) on
an everyday basis in many different professions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H4&gt;An Introduction to Calculus&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The introduction to calculus unit expands on your knowledge of mathematical functions to introduce ideas which will be critical for your future study of calculus. You will begin by learning the concepts of  sequences and series. You will learn how to identify different types of sequences, how to quickly find the sum of a several terms of a given sequence, and how to find the limit of a sequence, if it exists. You will also learn how to use the idea of limit in the context of rational functions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;P&gt; Next, you will learn about average rates of change. You will employ a limiting process to find the rate of change at a given moment, called the instantaneous rate of change. You will learn how to represent the instantaneous rate of change in the form of a derivative function. Finally, you will learn a bit about the &quot;reverse&quot; process, using the instantaneous rate of change information to determine the original function in a process known as integration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H4&gt;Statistical Inference&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The statistical inference unit will help us understand how we can
learn about the world by examining data from samples or subsets of
larger populations. For example, can a study of the diets of 400
people tell us whether high-fat diets lead to more heart disease in
the population as a whole? A big idea of this unit will
be the notion of random sampling. Mathematics will help us understand
how much the characteristics of a sample are likely to differ from those of the
whole population, and why some samples may be more likely to differ from
the population than others. We can use these results to estimate
certain characteristics of a population (what proportion of voters
favor withdrawing from Iraq?) or to test hypotheses about the world (are
17-year olds more likely to be involved in car accidents than 30-year
olds?).&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;P&gt;This course will challenge you to become an independent
mathematical thinker: proposing and testing your own conjectures,
applying mathematics to new situations, and creating your own models.
It will stretch the limits of your mathematical understanding as well
as exposing you to the power and beauty of modern mathematics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Materials:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Text - used only in second semester: Statistics, Informed Decisions Using Data, written by Michael Sullivan; other units are all supplemented by material supplied by the teacher.&lt;/p&gt;
Software: Microsoft Excel, Minitab 13, Sampling Distribution SIM program.
Calculators: Students are required to use a graphing calculator, preferably the TI-83.
Other Resources: Use is made of a variety of reference books and texts, websites, applets, and the like.
</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;H2&gt;Supplies&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Since we do not use a textbook in this course, you will need a well-organized 3-ring binder. Keep your class notes, homework, returned tests and quizzes, handouts, and blank (lined and graph) paper in it. Though there may not be official notebook checks during the year, an organized notebook and binder will prove to be a valuable resource at test time and throughout the course of the year.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;You will need a TI-84 or TI-83 plus calculator. You should have this calculator with you every class period. While you may use a TI-89 or a TI-Inspire for normal assignments, neither of these calculators will be allowed on tests or quizzes.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;College Algebra Reboot&lt;/H2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Most of you will take a mathematics course at some point in college. Many colleges now have placement exams designed to put you in the most appropriate college math class. Some of you will take these tests next spring or early next fall. In order to help you do well on these tests, we will be consistently reviewing algebra skills during the course of the year. Many classes will begin with a warm-up algebra review, and we will quiz on these algebra skills about once per cycle. You will usually NOT be permitted to use a calculator on these quizzes. Algebra quizzes will have the same value as any other quiz in determining your grade.
&lt;H2&gt; Daily Homework and Problem Sets&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Working together on homework assignments is allowed and encouraged. However, each student should be certain that she can do the problem herself before feeling that the assignment is complete. &lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Problem Sets will be handed out about 1 week before a scheduled test.  The problem set will be due on the day of the test. The problem set is primarily designed to be a review and practice exercise to prepare for the test. If a student wishes to retake a test (see section on tests and quizzes below) the problem set will be graded as part of the retake process. &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Tests &amp;amp; Quizzes&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;All tests will be announced well in advance, so you will have time
to study. You may not use your notes on tests, but you will usually be permitted a 3 x 5 notecard. You will almost always be allowed to use your calculators, although there will often be calculator-free sections on a test or a quiz. Retakes on tests are allowed if the student has scored below 83 percent on a test. A student who wishes to retake a test must meet with her teacher before the retake to go over the original test and the problem set, and the student must complete any additional review assigned by her teacher. The student's problem set will be graded along with the retake test, and the retake grade will be determined by taking one-third of the problem set grade and adding to it two-thirds of the retake test grade. The maximum score on a retake is 83 percent.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Quizzes will be short tasks given approximately once per week. Quizzes may consist of a new problem, a previously-discussed problem, or a problem assigned for homework.  There will be no opportunities to retake quizzes, but the lowest quiz grade or grades will be dropped at the end of the term. The number of quizzes to be dropped will depend on how many quizzes are given in the quarter. If 3 or fewer quizzes are given, none will be dropped. If between 4 and 7 quizzes are given, 1 will be dropped, and if 8 or more quizzes are given, 2 will be dropped. If you are absent for a quiz, that will be considered a &quot;drop&quot; except in special circumstances. &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Grading&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Your grade will be based on a variety of assessments. The primary
modes of assessment will be tests, quizzes, homework, projects, and
classroom participation. Other types of assessments include: group
work, individual or group presentations, nonroutine experiments, and
notebook checks.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The breakdown of how you will be graded each term is as follows
(applies at least to the first three quarters): Your grade for the quarter will be computed as a weighted average of tests, quizzes, and class effort. Tests will be worth 50% of the grade, quizzes 35%, and class effort 15%. As projects and other non-routine assessments are assigned, your teacher will inform you whether they will count as tests or quizzes, and how much contribution each will make to your overall term grade.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt; Due to the nature of the
fourth quarter for seniors being much shorter than the rest of the quarters, the
grades for fourth quarter may or may not be determined the same way
as the rest of the quarters. &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Class Participation&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Regular attendance is expected and important. If you&amp;#146;re
absent, you&amp;#146;re still responsible for any material missed! Make
up the work ASAP; find out what we did in class by checking westonmath.org, by calling a
classmate, or by sending email to your teacher, or by seeing your
teacher in school as soon as you return. If you miss a quiz or a test, you must meet with your teacher the day you return to school to schedule the makeup. If you absolutely must arrive at class
late or leave early, do so as rarely as possible.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;In terms of participation in the class, RESPECT is key to all
aspects of learning. You must respect your fellow classmates, your
teacher, as well as yourself. Listen to what others have to say, and
add your own insights and comments that will aid in classroom
discussion. Have a good sense of humor, but also exercise discretion
in your language and behavior. Treat all classroom materials and
property with respect.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Most importantly, commit yourself to a serious attitude and do the
work that&amp;#146;s expected of you in and out of class. Your success in
this course depends on how much effort you are willing to put in.
Take initiative for extra help. Help is always available- you just
need to ask for it. You are not alone in this venture.&lt;/P&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;P&gt; Here is the link to  &lt;A HREF=&quot;https://oli.web.cmu.edu/openlearning/forstudents/freecourses&quot;&gt;CARNEGIE MELLON ONLINE STATS.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is a link to the midterm course evaluation &lt;A HREF=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/my.weston.org/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dHFHNUtEQS0xWTBxaHVRTE0yT2xndnc6MA&quot;&gt;MIDTERM EVALUATION.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is a link to the calculus review videos &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.calculus-help.com/tutorials/&quot;&gt;CALCULUS VIDEOS.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is a link to an interesting series video &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://vihart.com/doodling/infinity-elephants.mp4&quot;&gt;INFINITY ELEPHANTS.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; There are some good algebra review activities and tutorials at the &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.wtamu.edu/academic/anns/mps/math/mathlab/col_algebra/&quot;&gt;VIRTUAL MATH LAB.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link for, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;teachers/monzj/precalc2/College Math Requirements 2012.pdf&quot;&gt;COLLEGE MATH REQUIREMENTS.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link for, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;teachers/monzj/precalc2/Area Under Curves by Trapezoids.xlsx&quot;&gt;DEFINITE INTEGRAL SPREADSHEET.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link for, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://stattrek.com/AP-Statistics-2/Survey-Sampling-Bias.aspx?Tutorial=Stat&quot;&gt;SAMPLING BIAS.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; For the applet for dice rolling, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://academic.evergreen.edu/curricular/doingscience/flash/dice.html&quot;&gt;DICE ROLLING ACTIVITY.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; For the applet to find areas under curves, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.math.ucla.edu/~ronmiech/Java_Applets/Riemann/index.html&quot;&gt;AREAS UNDER CURVES&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;For the link to the online lessons about sampling, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://ccnmtl.columbia.edu/projects/qmss/samples_and_sampling/introduction.html&quot;&gt;SAMPLING LESSONS&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; For the sketchpad file on slopes of curves, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/precalc2/Slopes of Curves on Sketchpad.gsp&quot;&gt;SLOPES OF CURVES ON SKETCHPAD&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; For the tutorial on approximating areas under curves, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.karlscalculus.org/calc10_0.html#p1s5&quot;&gt;AREA UNDER A CURVE TUTORIAL&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt; For the sequences and series spreadsheet, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/precalc1/SequenceSeriesSpreadsheet.xls&quot;&gt;SEQUENCE AND SERIES SPREADSHEET&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt; For instructions on using the spreadsheets, click &lt;A  HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/precalc2/Using Spreadsheets to Understand Sequences and Series.pdf&quot; &gt; HERE.&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt; For a copy of the Z- or T-probability tables, click on &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/precalc2/NormalProbabilityTables.pdf&quot;&gt;Z- and T-TABLES&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;&lt;P&gt;For the MINITAB Random Rectangle sheet, click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/precalc2/Random Rectangles.MPJ&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;For the Sampling Distributions Activity click &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/monzj/precalc2/Sampling SIM_1.exe&quot;&gt;HERE.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">361</column>
            <column name="full_name">Calculus AB</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Calc AB</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">&lt;B&gt;Students in this course will study properties of elementary functions and concepts of calculus (limits, derivatives, integrals, and applications). This course will prepare students to take the Advance Placement Calculus AB examination in May.&lt;/B&gt;</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H1&gt;&lt;CENTER&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt; WELCOME TO AB
CALCULUS&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;The Course &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Calculus AB is a course in single-variable
   calculus that includes techniques and applications of the
   &lt;B&gt;derivative&lt;/b&gt;, techniques and applications of the &lt;B&gt;definite
   integral&lt;/b&gt;, and the &lt;B&gt;Fundamental Theorem of
   Calculus&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;It is equivalent to at least a semester of
   calculus at most colleges and universities, perhaps to a year of
   calculus at some.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;&lt;B&gt;Algebraic&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;B&gt;numerical&lt;/b&gt;, and
   &lt;B&gt;graphical representations&lt;/b&gt; are emphasized throughout the
   course.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;&lt;B&gt;Graphing calculators&lt;/b&gt; are a necessity
   in class, on homework, and on the AP Examination. It allows you
   to appreciate connections and more deeply understand the
   concepts.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Two years of algebra and a year of
   geometry&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;A strong grounding in elementary functions - their properties, their graphs, and the algebra of functions.  Also the language of functions (domain and range, odd and even, periodic, symmetry, zeros, intercepts, etc.)  The values of trigonometric functions at 0, pi/6, pi/4, pi/3, pi/2, and their multiples.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;A willingness to work both in and out of
   class.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;A willingness to collaborate with
   classmates to foster mutual understanding,&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt; &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;P&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Goals&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;OL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should be able to work with
   functions represented in a variety of ways: graphical, numerical,
   analytical, or verbal. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;They should understand the connections among
   these representations.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should understand the meaning of
   the derivative in terms of a rate of change and local linear
   approximation and should be able to use derivatives to solve a
   variety of problems.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should understand the meaning of
   the definite integral both as a limit of Riemann sums and as the
   net accumulation of a rate of change and should be able to use
   integrals to solve a variety of problems.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should understand the relationship
   between the derivative and the definite integral as expressed in
   both parts of the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should be able to communicate
   mathematics both orally and in well-written sentences and should
   be able to explain solutions to problems.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should be able to model a written



   description of a physical situation with a function, a
   differential equation, or an integral.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should be able to use technology
   to help solve problems, experiment, interpret results, and verify
   conclusions.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should be able to determine the
   reasonableness of solutions, including sign, size, relative
   accuracy, and units of measurement.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Students should develop an appreciation of
   calculus as a coherent body of knowledge and as a human
   accomplishment.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Grading&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Quizzes&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Tests&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;P&gt;*****&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;All or parts of tests and quizzes may be
&lt;/font&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot; COLOR=&quot;#003399&quot;&gt;&lt;B&gt;NONCALCULATOR&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/font&gt;*****&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Classwork and participation (used for borderline grades
   )&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Projects (varies)&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Homework&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Given most nights.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Collected some of the time.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Loses credit for each day late.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Late homework receives no credit after 5
   school days unless your are absent and an agreement is made
   between the teacher and student.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Make-up&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;P&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Homework should be made up as soon as
   possible when you are absent on the day it was
   assigned.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Tests and quizzes should be made up when
   you return unless you've missed some important
   information.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;If more time is needed you must make
   arrangements with the teacher either by e-mail or in person when
   you return.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt;Generally there are no make-ups due to a
   poor score.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;P&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;H2&gt;&lt;FONT FACE=&quot;Arial&quot;&gt; WEBSITES &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://archives.math.utk.edu/topics/calculus.html&quot;&gt; http://archives.math.utk.edu/topics/calculus.html &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://people.hofstra.edu/faculty/Stefan_Waner/RealWorld/tccalcp.html&quot;&gt; http://people.hofstra.edu/faculty/Stefan_Waner/RealWorld/tccalcp.html &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt; Related Rates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.mecca.org/~halfacre/MATH/lesson14.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.mecca.org/`halfacre/MATH/lesson14.htm
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;
http://www.elmhurst.edu/~abigailh/fa00/math151-01/m151-01worksheets/worksheet8/worksheet8key.html&quot;&gt;http://www.elmhurst.edu/~abigailh/fa00/math151-01/m151-01worksheets/worksheet8/worksheet8key.html
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">371</column>
            <column name="full_name">Calculus BC</column>
            <column name="short_name">NULL</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">Calc BC</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">The topics in this course range from elementary calculus concepts to infinite series and differential equations. This course prepares students to take the Advanced Placement Calculus BC examination in May.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H2&gt;&lt;B&gt;Who should take BC Calculus?&lt;/B&gt;&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Calculus BC &lt;/B&gt;is a two semester course designed to provide
students with a strong background in Calculus, enabling the students
to succesfully pursue further mathematics courses at the most
challenging universities. Students should expect&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;one to one and a half hours of homework on each day that class
   meets.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;challenging problems both in class and for homework&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;to use the calculator (TI-83) as a tool for investigation and
   calculation&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;to use a spreadsheet for occasional problems and at least one
   project&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;problems on tests that require them to use the ideas of the
   course in a new way&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;to present their work at the board&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
Course Content:
&lt;p&gt;
Introduction to calculus, absolute value inequalities in one and two variables, function review, parametric equations, polar curves, definition of derivative, definition of limit, limit theorems, trigonometric limits, limits at infinity and infinite limits, horizontal and vertical asymptotes, continuity, the Intermediate Value Theorem, the Extreme Value Theorem, the relationship between continuity and differentiability, differentiation formulas, derivatives of trigonometric functions, the chain rule, implicit differentiation, slope fields.
&lt;p&gt;
Higher order derivatives, related rates, linear and quadratic approximation, relative error, Newton?s Method, finding maxima and minima, Rolle?s Theorem and the Mean Value Theorem, applications of the Mean Value Theorem, monotonic functions and the first derivative test, concavity and points of inflection, curve sketching, applied maximum and minimum problems, derivatives of parametrically defined curves, antiderivatives,  sigma notation, area under a curve, the definite integral, the Fundamental Theorem of Calculus, average value of a function, calculating definite integrals, area between curves, volumes by slicing, volumes of solids of revolution, area in polar coordinates, arclength.
&lt;p&gt;
Work, inverse functions, the Inverse Function Theorem, the natural logarithm and its derivative, the exponential function and its derivative, general logarithmic and exponential functions, logarithmic differentiation, exponential growth and decay, differential equations, inverse trigonometric functions, L?H?pital?s Rule, integration by parts, reduction formulas, integrating powers of trigonometric functions, trigonometric substitution, integration by partial fractions, by substitution, approximate integration, improper integrals, Euler?s Method
&lt;p&gt;
Sequences, series, convergence and divergence of series, geometric series, the harmonic and p-series, alternating series with error bound, tests for convergence and divergence including the n-th term divergence test, integral test with error bound, comparison and limit comparison tests, alternating series convergence test, ratio test and root test, absolute convergence, power series, interval and radius of convergence, Taylor and Maclaurin series, representing functions as power series, Lagrange error bound for Taylor polynomials 
&lt;p&gt;
TEXTS: &lt;i&gt;Calculus, 5th Edition &lt;/i&gt;by James Stewart, published by Brooks/Cole, 2003.

</column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;P&gt;Timely completion of homework is expected and students will be
occasionally asked to submit a designated problem from their homework
assignment. (No substitutions allowed.) Results from these homework
quizzes may impact a student's quarter grade. Of course, sincere effort
on homework assignments is essential to success in any course.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Written work must include detailed work leading to a solution.
Otherwise, credit will not be given.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Working together on homework assignments is allowed and
encouraged. However, each student's solution should look different.
Solutions that are identical may not be given credit.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt; &lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Quarterly grades are based on&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;exams&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;projects, when applicable&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;designated homework assignments&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;homework quizzes&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;P&gt;For information about the AP Exam in BC Calculus go to &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/article/0,1281,151-162-0-4348,00.html&quot;&gt;AP
Central&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">381</column>
            <column name="full_name">Advanced Placement Computer Science</column>
            <column name="short_name">AP Comp Sci</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">AP CS</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">The emphasis of this course is on the logical thinking and understanding of computers necessary to solve problems by writing computer programs. The course studies programming methodology, algorithms, and data structures.  Students will learn the subset of Java identified by the College Entrance Examination Board. The course generally follows the syllabus suggested for preparation for the Advanced Placement Computer Science AB examination, including the current case study. Students need have no prior knowledge of Java. Students with no programming background should expect to spend significant amounts of time working with computers during the first quarter or should take Computer Science: Introduction to Programming (Course 336) prior to enrolling in this course. Work may be done using school computers or on the student&amp;#8217;s home computer. Successful completion of this course prepares students for the Advanced Placement Computer Science AB examination in May. (Students who find the first semester overly challenging may elect to take the A level examination instead.)</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;HTML&gt;
&lt;!--This file created 4:12 PM  9/7/2004 by Claris Home Page version 3.0--&gt;
&lt;HEAD&gt;
   &lt;TITLE&gt;ATIP Course Info&lt;/TITLE&gt;
   &lt;META NAME=GENERATOR CONTENT=&quot;Claris Home Page 3.0&quot;&gt;
   &lt;X-CLARIS-WINDOW TOP=52 BOTTOM=603 LEFT=8 RIGHT=538&gt;
   &lt;X-CLARIS-TAGVIEW MODE=minimal&gt;
&lt;/HEAD&gt;
&lt;BODY BGCOLOR=&quot;#FFFFFF&quot;&gt;
&lt;H1&gt;Advanced Placement Computer Science (Course 381)&lt;/H1&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Course Description:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;The emphasis of this course is on the logical thinking and
understanding of computers necessary to solce problems by writing
computer programs. The course studies programming methodology,
algorithms, and data structures. Students will learn the subset of
Java identified by the College Entrance Examination Board. The course
generally follows the syllabus suggested for preparation for the
Advanced placement Computer Science AB examination including the
current case study. Students need have no prior knowledge of Java.
Students with no programming background should expect to spend
significant amounts of time working with computers during the first
quarter or should take Computer Science: Introduction to Programming
(Course 336) prior to enrolling in this course.Work may be done using
school computers or on the student's home computer. Successful
completion of this course prepares students for the Advanced
placement Computer Science AB examination in May. (Students who find
the first semester overly challenging may elect to take the Computer
Science A level examination instead.)&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Themes:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;OL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;Producing code that can be read and modified by future
   programmers.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Using effectively the object oriented paradigm..&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Understanding discrete storage and manipulation of data&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Analyzing the inter-relationships and effectiveness of data
   structures and algorithms.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;Managing complexity.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Student Outcomes:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Students will&amp;#133;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;OL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;write code in Java to solve problems.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;become familiar with a larger Java program (the Case Study)
   and be able to modify it as requested.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;prepare for an Advanced Placement examination in Computer
   Science.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;use and compare different classes from the standard Java
   library.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;improve their ability to manage their time to meet overlapping
   assignments.&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;explore many aspects of Computer Science as an academic
   discipline.&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Course Content:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 1, Objects, Inheritance, and Recursion: &lt;/B&gt; Students
learn to create and use simple Java classes including abstract
classes and interfaces. Recursion is used to process linked lists.
Students study discrete methods for binary storage of integers.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 2, Containers, Sorting and Searching: &lt;/B&gt;Students use
arrays and ArrayLists to store data and study common algorithms for
searching and sorting data. Techniques for file I/O are used. Big-O
notation is introduced for comparing algorithms.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 3, Polymorphism, Exception Handling, and Java Linked
Lists: &lt;/B&gt;Students explore polymorphism and inheritance in greater
depth, learn techniques for handling errors, and practice creating
their own linked lists.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;B&gt;Topic 4, Advanced Java Data Structures: &lt;/B&gt;Students explore
trees, hashing, maps, graphs, and other structures and their use in
problem solving.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H2&gt;Materials:&lt;/H2&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Texts: &lt;I&gt;Computing Concepts with Java Essentials&lt;/I&gt; by Cay
Horstmann (John Wiley and Sons, 2003 third edition) and the
accompanying &lt;I&gt;Advanced Placement Study Guide&lt;/I&gt; by Fran Trees and
Cay Horstmann (John Wiley and Sons, 2004), both supplemented
extensively by teacher-written materials.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Videos/film: &lt;I&gt;Sorting Out Sorting&lt;/I&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Software: For most of the first quarter students use Prof J available as a part of Dr. Scheme.  Thereafter students use JCreator LE to develop Java programs.  In addition the Java classes for the Case Study will be made available through the assignments page or can be obtained from the College Board. Links to these materials can be found on the Resouces/news page.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;/BODY&gt;
&lt;/HTML&gt;
</column>
            <column name="policies">APCS Policies

Success in AP Computer Science requires enthusiasm and commitment. A large number of assignments are given, and because students work at different paces most programming assignments have flexible due dates.  (Small paper and pencil exercises have significantly less flexibility.) Often submitted work is returned to students for revision if the work does not provide clear evidence that the student has mastered the concept or skill that motivated the assignment.  Students are expected to attach their old code to the new code so that the improvements can be noted. Students need to read program specifications carefully and ask for clarification by proposing examples when specifications are unclear.&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

Students will be given progress reports several times each quarter.  Each program and paper assignment is listed along with a â€œcurrent gradeâ€:  B indicates competent work that demonstrated understanding of the central concept or skill needed to complete the work.  A indicates work that went beyond competence by using especially clear or elegant approaches to the task, by an unusual freedom from minor errors or because the work met an optional challenging requirement identified as â€œA level only.â€  N indicates work that shows a good effort on the task but that does not yet provide convincing evidence of mastery.  Students are expected to read the teacherâ€™s comments carefully and to then modify and resubmit the work.  Such modified work can change the grade to B (but not A).  There is no limit to the number of times work may be resubmitted except for the realities of time!  F indicates that no significant work has yet been submitted on this problem although a significant number of students have completed the problem by this point in time. &lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

By the end of the first quarter students should have a realistic understanding of the degree of difficulty of the work and the effort and time commitment needed on their part to succeed. Those who find the work overly demanding my elect to prepare for the A level exam or to work at the Honors rather than the AP level.  Each of these levels results in a decrease in the number of assignments that need to be completed.  Students still attend all classes but may have additional lab time in place of classroom presentations of some new material, especially in the second semester. &lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</column>
            <column name="resources">The course uses a Java IDE.  JCreator is the current IDE in use.&lt;br&gt;        &lt;P&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
For most of the Java work you will need to have the Java compiler installed on your computer. Java is a product of Sun Microsystems. The latest java is Java 7.0; the school computers currently are using Java 6.0; I recommend you install 6.0 at home for consistency.. You need the JDK (Java Developers Kit) You can download the JDK  from  &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://java.sun.com/javase/downloads/index.jsp&quot;&gt; Java &lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After installing Java, download and install  JCreator LE from &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.jcreator.com/download.tm&quot;&gt;JCreator&lt;/a&gt; the version used at school is 4.5  listed as a  JCreator Classic&lt;br&gt;
A useful summary of the installation process is on line at &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.skylit.com/javamethods/faqs/gettingstarted.html&quot;&gt;Skylight publishing&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

When bringing work to and from class it is simplest to transfer just the *.java files and add them to your project.
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

Information from the College Board can be obtained at 
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://apcentral.collegeboard.com/apc/public/courses/teachers_corner/4483.html&quot;&gt; Computer Science A&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

 Available text files for download to use with the typing monkeys:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/Melville.txt&quot;&gt; Melville short story&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/Twain.txt&quot;&gt; Twain short story&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/Goethe.txt&quot;&gt; German text&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/Dante.txt&quot;&gt; Italian text&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/Balzac.txt&quot;&gt; French text&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/AllsWell.txt&quot;&gt; Shakespeare play&lt;/a&gt;  
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/mccowand/apcs/Monkey/SpanishPoems.txt&quot;&gt; Spanish poems&lt;/a&gt; </column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
        <table name="courses">
            <column name="number">391</column>
            <column name="full_name">Advanced Placement Statistics</column>
            <column name="short_name">AP Statistics</column>
            <column name="schedule_name">AP Stats</column>
            <column name="semesters">12</column>
            <column name="num_occurrences">5</column>
            <column name="description">This course covers the statistics syllabus prepared by the College Board and is equivalent to a college-level statistics course.
Major topics include descriptive statistics; data collection, sampling, and surveys;
probability; and statistical inference including confidence intervals and tests of significance.
Students will use graphing calculators with statistical capabilities as well as selected computer statistics software.
This is a course for students interested in pursuing areas of study requiring statistical analysis of experiments and those who have high motivation and demonstrated mathematical achievement who are interested in working at the college level.
Other students interested in statistics should enroll in Precalculus Part Two (Course 352), where a unit on statistical inference is taught.</column>
            <column name="info">&lt;H1&gt;Who should take AP Statistics?&lt;/H1&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Juniors and seniors who are interested in pursuing careers that
require statistical analysis of experimental data or survey data
(i.e. biology, genetics, social science, psychology, economics,
political science and business, etc.) are candidates for this course.
As a prerequisite, students must have a strong Algebra II and Precalculus,
Part I
background.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;H3&gt;Technology&lt;/H3&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Students will&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;UL&gt;
   &lt;LI&gt;use a TI-83 or TI-83 Plus calculator&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;use the MINITAB statistical software, available on the Weston
   High School computer system&lt;/LI&gt;
   
   &lt;LI&gt;use various interactive websites &lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Course Description:  
&lt;P&gt;
This course covers the statistics syllabus prepared by the College Board and is equivalent to a college level statistics course.  Major topics include descriptive statistics, data collection, sampling and surveys, probability and statistical inference including confidence intervals and tests of significance.  Students will use graphing calculators with statistical capabilities as well as selected computer statistics software.  This is a course for students interested in pursuing areas of study requiring statistical analysis of experiments, and who have high motivation and demonstrated mathematical achievement.  Other students interested in statistics should enroll in Precalculus, Part II (Course 352) where a unit on statistical inference is taught.
&lt;P&gt;

Course Content:
&lt;p&gt;
There are four major topic areas in AP Statistics:  Exploring Data, Research Design, Probability, and Inference.
&lt;p&gt;
	Exploring Data involves using both numerical and visual techniques to study patterns and departures from those patterns in sets of data. This information is used to assess the quality and usefulness of the data set as well as to develop conjectures about the information contained in the data. Numerical methods include measures of center, spread, and location, as well as correlation and regression coefficients to observe relationships between various measures on the same ?subjects?. Graphical methods include boxplots, stemplots, histograms, and scatterplots. Both numerical and visual methods are used to compare data sets, and special methods for the evaluation of categorical data are employed.
&lt;p&gt;
	Research Design involves deciding what and how to measure as well as developing a plan to collect reliable data through experiment or survey. Students will learn methods of  data collection designed to reduce bias, control for confounding factors, and generate reliable numbers. They will also study the principles of sampling and understand the variation inherent in repeated sampling. Students will construct their own experiments and surveys and carry them out to observe these principles in action.

&lt;p&gt;
	Probability involves the use of both simulation and probability theory to predict what the distribution of data should look like in a particular situation. It is the tool used to anticipate the distribution of data under certain assumptions, and thus provides the basis for testing whether those assumptions are accurate. The techniques of mathematical probability (including conditional probability) will be studied, as well as the use of simulations to estimate probabilities where theoretical methods are insufficient.

&lt;p&gt;
	Inference involves drawing conclusions about a population from data on a sample of that population. The students will learn how to construct confidence intervals for a population parameter, as well as how to conduct various tests of significance. In particular, we will cover tests for the value of a mean or proportion, tests for the difference of two means or proportions, tests for the ?goodness-of-fit? of data to a proposed distribution, tests for the independence of two measures, and tests for the slope of the least-squares regression line. Students will learn about the relationship between confidence intervals and hypothesis tests as well. An important area of study will be the choice of an appropriate confidence interval or test for the particular issue to be studied.
&lt;p&gt;

Text:  &lt;i&gt;Stats: Modeling the World&lt;/i&gt;, Bock, Velleman, DeVeaux, Pearson, 2007. </column>
            <column name="policies">&lt;p&gt;AP Statistics is a college-level course. All students taking AP Statistics are expected to approach the course with the seriousness of purpose and motivation expected of students in a college class. Students who do not exhibit such qualities will be asked to drop the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In statistical work, results are rarely obvious or intuitive. Rather, the researcher must explain clearly the kinds of data collected, the analytical methods chosen, and the conclusions drawn. These explanations must be clear and thorough. Work unaccompanied by such explanations is, in general, not acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Working together on homework assignments is allowed and encouraged. However, each student should be certain that she can do the problem herself before feeling that the assignment is complete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;For the first 3 terms, quarterly grades are based on
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;LI&gt;	quizzes and tests&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;projects, when applicable&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;class participation and effort&lt;/LI&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Quizzes, tests, and projects combine for 90% of a term grade, while class participation and effort account for 10%. All tests have the same value; the total of all quizzes for a term equals one test; project values will be assigned based on the time &amp; effort required for the project (they can vary from between 0.5 tests and 2 tests).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Tests:&lt;/H4&gt; Two tests will be given in each of the first 3 quarters. Tests will follow the AP format, with a multiple choice section and a free response section. Students will be allowed to use their calculator and the AP &quot;formula sheet&quot; on all tests. Students will not be allowed notecards or notes in addition to or in lieu of the AP &quot;formula sheet&quot; on any tests. Retakes on tests are allowed if the student has scored below an 83 on the original test. A student who wishes to retake a test must meet with her teacher before the retake to go over the original test and the problem set, and the student must complete any additional review assigned by her teacher. The student's problem set will be graded along with the retake test, and the retake grade will be determined by taking one-third of the problem set grade and adding to it two-thirds of the retake test grade, up to a maximum of 83 percent.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;&lt;H4&gt;Quizzes:&lt;/H4&gt; Quizzes will be short (one question) 20-30 minute tasks given approximately once per cycle. Quizzes may consist of a new problem, a previously-discussed problem, or a problem assigned for homework. Quizzes may not be retaken, but the low quiz grades in each quarter will be dropped, according to the following rule: if there are fewer than 3 quizzes in a term,  none will be dropped; from 4 to 6 quizzes, 1 will be dropped; more than 6 quizzes, 2 will be dropped.&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;When a student is absent from class on the day of a test, the test must be made up within four school days. In the case of an extended illness, adjustments to the time period will be made. If it has not been made up within that period the student will receive a zero for that quiz/test. If a student is absent on the day of a quiz, the student may make up the quiz on the next day he/she is present in class, or the student may elect to have the missed quiz be one of the dropped quizzes for that term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;H4&gt;Problem Sets: &lt;/H4&gt;Problem Sets will be handed out about 1 week before a scheduled test.  The problem set will be due on the day of the test. The problem set is primarily designed to be a review and practice exercise to prepare for the test. If a student wishes to retake a test (see section on tests and quizzes below) the problem set will be graded as part of the retake process. See the section of tests above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;P&gt; The AP exam takes place in early May, at the end of the (abbreviated) 4th quarter for seniors, and roughly in the middle of the 4th quarter for all underclass students. As a result of this schedule the course is conducted in a different way in the 4th quarter. For seniors, the following are the main activities in the 4th quarter: (1) completion of the student's independent research project, (2) taking a comprehensive exam, with emphasis on problems involving knowledge from multiple sections of the curriculum, and (3) preparing a review outline of a specific topic and leading the class through some review activities. The underclass students will complete these activities as well, and after the AP exam they will engage in several small projects designed to either deepen their understanding of topics already covered or to introduced new methods of statistical analysis. Fourth-quarter grades will be calculated differently than the grades of the previous 3 quarters, with the exact percentages to be determined by the time devoted to each activity in a given class section.
&lt;/P&gt;

&lt;P&gt;Semester grades are computed by finding the average of the two quarters that make up the particular semester. The year grade is the average of the four quarters. For seniors, the 4th quarter will be weighted one-half as much as the other 3 quarters. &lt;/p&gt;

</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;P&gt;Read the following article:  &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/19/magazine/shopping-habits.html?pagewanted=all&quot;&gt;HOW COMPANIES LEARN YOUR SECRETS&quot;.&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;Here are some links to the correlation activities &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.westonmath.org/teachers/monzj/alg2h/Scatterplot%20Correlation%20Exercise.ftm&quot;&gt;FATHOM CORRELATION EXERCISE&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://istics.net/stat/Correlations/&quot;&gt;CORRELATION GAME&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.ruf.rice.edu/~lane/stat_sim/reg_by_eye/index.html&quot;&gt;REGRESSION BY EYE GAME&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is a link to the midterm course evaluation &lt;A HREF=&quot;https://docs.google.com/a/my.weston.org/spreadsheet/viewform?formkey=dHFHNUtEQS0xWTBxaHVRTE0yT2xndnc6MA&quot;&gt;MIDTERM EVALUATION.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link to  &lt;A HREF=&quot;https://oli.web.cmu.edu/openlearning/forstudents/freecourses&quot;&gt;CARNEGIE MELLON ONLINE STATS.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is a link to  &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.unpracticalmath.com/applets/virtual_dice.html&quot;&gt;VIRTUAL DICE.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;P&gt; If you need some extra review, or if you find our textbook a bit unclear, try these online resources:  &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.stattrek.com&quot;&gt;STAT TREK.&lt;/A&gt; and  &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://onlinestatbook.com&quot;&gt;THE ONLINE STAT TEXTBOOK.&lt;/A&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link for the &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.causeweb.org/repository/Minitab/Minitab.pdf&quot;&gt;INTRO TO MINITAB.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link for the &lt;A HREF=&quot;teachers/monzj/apstats/TextingData.mpj&quot;&gt;TEXTING DATA.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Here is the link for the &lt;A HREF=&quot;teachers/monzj/apstats/WATER TEST DATA.xlsx&quot;&gt;WATER TEST DATABASE.&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; You can find a program for the Chi-Square Goodness of Fit Test on the TI-83 at &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://staweb.sta.cathedral.org/departments/math/mhansen/public_html/01stat/programs/chisqgof.htm&quot;&gt;Chi-Square Test.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt; Log in to the probability experiment at &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://veconlab.econ.virginia.edu/login.php&quot;&gt;Probability Experiment.&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;&lt;P&gt;For information about the AP Exam in AP Statistics go to &lt;A HREF=&quot;http://www.collegeboard.com/ap/students/statistics/index.html&quot;&gt;AP
Central&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;
&lt;P&gt;For the activity on Normal Quantile Plots go to &lt;A HREF=&quot;/teachers/gonzalezd/apstats/normalplot.mpj&quot;&gt;NORMAL PLOTS&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/P&gt;</column>
            <column name="has_assgts">1</column>
        </table>
    </database>
</pma_xml_export>