<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
- phpMyAdmin XML Dump
- version 3.3.7deb7
- http://www.phpmyadmin.net
-
- Host: outhouse.wildwoodweb.net
- Generation Time: Aug 28, 2012 at 02:25 PM
- Server version: 5.0.51
- PHP Version: 5.3.3-7+squeeze9
-->

<pma_xml_export version="1.0">
    <!--
    - Database: 'wmdhs'
    -->
    <database name="wmdhs">
        <!-- Table departments -->
        <table name="departments">
            <column name="news">&lt;h2&gt;New Department Head&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please welcome James McLaughlin as the new head of the Math Department for grades 6–12!&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="how_to_use">&lt;h2&gt;How to Use the New Westonmath App&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This app is your source of information for math courses at Weston High School.
The tab right below this one lists some of its features, but here&amp;#8217;s enough to get you started:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This page is called &lt;b&gt;Home&lt;/b&gt;.
You can get to it through the &lt;b&gt;Home&lt;/b&gt; menu,
which is always the first one at the top of every page.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To find information about a particular course,
click on the &lt;b&gt;Courses&lt;/b&gt; menu.
You will see a list of all our courses and their sections,
listed by teacher and block number.
Click on any course to read basic information about it,
including the course description and a list of sections,
each with its teacher, block, and room number.
Click on any column header to sort by that column.
Click again to reverse the sort.
Click on a section&amp;#8217;s block to see assignments for that section.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Course pages also have tabs along the top (below the three standard Westonmath menus).
You can click on any tab to read about the course information,
resources, policies, and news.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
 &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You can also get to any section&amp;#8217;s assignments
by clicking on the section in the &lt;b&gt;Courses&lt;/b&gt; menu.
The current assignment is always listed first, followed by any upcoming assignments that have already been posted, followed by all past assignments.
You can choose whether to display 2, 5, 10, or all past assignments.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The third menu lists all the &lt;b&gt;Faculty&lt;/b&gt; in our Department.
Clicking on the icon to the left of a name takes you to that teacher&amp;#8217;s home page,
which includes a list of the courses s/he is currrently teaching.
Clicking on the icon to the right opens up your favorite email program,
with a new message addressed to that teacher.
If you are using a machine that doesn&amp;#8217;t have an identified email client,
this option will not work.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The &lt;b&gt;Home&lt;/b&gt; page also contains some general information about the Math Department, such as resources, news, and a puzzle that is often (well...occasionally) updated.
Check out the tabs in the accordion!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If you spot any bugs, send email to Mr. Davidson (DavidsonL@weston.org).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
 
&lt;/p&gt;</column>
            <column name="resources">&lt;h2&gt;WHS Math Department Internal Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/AcademicSupport_10-11.pdf&quot;&gt;Academic Support&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;WHS Math Team&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathteam.westonmath.org/&quot;&gt;Math Team&amp;#8217;s homepage&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/files/teachers/davidsonl/mathteam/permission-form-2011-12.pdf&quot;&gt;Math Team Permission Form&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mathteam.westonmath.org/calendar-2008-09.pdf&quot;&gt;Math Team Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;External Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Alexander Bogomolny always has a wealth of fascinating challenges at his &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cut-the-knot.org&quot;&gt;Cut the Knot&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			
			
			&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://coolmath.com/&quot;&gt;Cool Math&lt;/a&gt; site contains useful links to a lot of other interesting math sites.&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			
			&lt;li&gt;Get your math puzzles &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mathpuzzle.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;br /&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www-groups.dcs.st-and.ac.uk:80/%7ehistory/index.html&quot;&gt;history of math&lt;/a&gt; provides a useful context that can inform and enliven what you&amp;#8217;re learning.&lt;br&gt;
				&lt;br&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;</column>
            <column name="puzzle">&lt;h2&gt;The Chess Players&lt;/h2&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Josh MacKeetch, his sister, his son, and his daughter all play chess.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The best player’s twin and the worst player are of the opposite sex.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The best player and the worst player are of the same age.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Who plays the best game of chess? &lt;/p&gt;
</column>
        </table>
    </database>
</pma_xml_export>